<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
  <title>Timothy B Smith</title>
  <link href="http://ttimsmith.com/"/>
  <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="http://ttimsmith.com/feed.xml"/>
  <updated>2013-08-12T14:32:17-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://ttimsmith.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Tim Smith</name>
    <email>smith@ttimsmith.com</email>
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/no-one-likes-a-soggy-sandwich</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/no-one-likes-a-soggy-sandwich"/>
    <title>No One Likes a Soggy Sandwich</title>
    <published>2013-08-12T14:30:17-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-08-12T14:30:17-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There’s an ocean of fine-looking UIs on Dribbble that fall apart faster than a soggy sandwich when you really get down to the UX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Justin is just on a roll. His latests blog posts hit the nail right on the head, and this one is no different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This all comes down to one question: as designers, will we let our profession become mere decoration? As Justin points out, unsolicited redesigns, and pretty user interfaces, are a dime a dozen. You and I can aspire to something better.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/on-hearing-from-new-people</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/on-hearing-from-new-people"/>
    <title>On Hearing from New People</title>
    <published>2013-08-12T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-08-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…as an industry we do need to hear from more people from different situations whether it be freelance, startups, agencies big or small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m usually hesitant to share articles that talk about there being a “web celebrity” problem, but this is not that type of article. The author makes a good point in saying that most who have that “status”, if you want to call it that, have earned it. They’re great at what they do. The real issue is getting more people comfortable with sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was just talking about this with a designer friend of mine the other day. There are a lot of people doing interesting work, but become intimidated, and think they have nothing to contribute. You do. We all do. Write about it. You have the power to make our industry better.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/jekyll-post-automaters</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/jekyll-post-automaters"/>
    <title>Jekyll Post Automaters</title>
    <published>2013-08-12T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-08-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Turns out, ‘automaters’ isn’t a word. Anyway, this weekend, I &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/moving-over-to-jekyll/&quot;&gt;moved this blog to Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. I’m a sucker for making things easier, so I created some scripts and templates to automate the process of creating a new post. The original script was created by &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.codykrieger.com/&quot;&gt;Cody Krieger&lt;/a&gt;, but I made some simple modifications to make it all work with Alfred. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an important note, the script &lt;strong&gt;does not&lt;/strong&gt; add a date to the name of the file like Jekyll wants you to. The reason for that is, I work with a &lt;code&gt;_drafts&lt;/code&gt; folder, and those files aren’t supposed to have a date. I use a &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeffreysambells.com/2013/02/01/jekyll-draft-publishing-plugin&quot;&gt;great plugin by Jeffrey Sambells&lt;/a&gt; which puts a date on my files when they’re ready to publish.  If you don’t want it to work that way, you just replace the &lt;code&gt;filename&lt;/code&gt; variable with &lt;code&gt;&quot;#{Time.now.strftime(&#39;%Y-%m-%d&#39;)}-#{title.parameterize}.md&quot;&lt;/code&gt; and that will create a publish-ready file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be creating a screencast in the next couple days that will go step-by-step on setting all this up, but in the meantime, feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ttimsmith&quot;&gt;@reply&lt;/a&gt; me on Twitter with any questions.  &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/moving-over-to-jekyll</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/moving-over-to-jekyll"/>
    <title>Moving Over to Jekyll</title>
    <published>2013-08-10T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-08-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yes, you read that correctly. I’ve moved this blog over to Jekyll. I don’t know why I didn’t do this sooner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t know about &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, it’s a static site generator built with Ruby. I was really scared to move over, mostly dreading the work that would go into migrating all of my WordPress posts.  I was able to easily create post formats with the help of some code that my pal &lt;a href=&quot;http://avclark.com&quot;&gt;Adam Clark&lt;/a&gt; pointed me to. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it did take me about 8 total hours to migrate and design, I already feel it’s worth it.  I’ve created an Alfred Workflow that allows me to easily create new posts, with the appropriate &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/frontmatter/&quot;&gt;front-matter&lt;/a&gt;, and I’ll be recording a screencast on how to do that in the next couple days. The feed should redirect, but if not, you can grab it &lt;a href=&quot;/feed.xml&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this isn’t a huge thing, but I’m so excited about doing this. I’m even thinking about creating a Tim Likes to Teach course on it. If you’d like to see the source of the site, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ttimsmith/ttimsmith.com&quot;&gt;see it on Github&lt;/a&gt;. Feel free to look at the code and submit issues if you see wonky stuff (It’s totally possible. Data migrations aren’t my thing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-are-you-anti-wordpress-now&quot;&gt;So Are You Anti-WordPress Now?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not at all. I love WordPress. I’ve been working with WordPress for years. However, I work on this site a lot, and I found myself very frustrated with how WordPress handles a simple blog. The honest truth, WordPress is too much for just a blog these days. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a web editor had become tiresome for me. I like writing posts in Byword. Byword has WordPress publishing support, but no support for post formats, and the process of setting custom fields is not really well done. So in the end, I had to write the post in Byword, and then go to the web editor anyway to set values for the posts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Jekyll, I type &lt;code&gt;jekyll  [post-format] [title]&lt;/code&gt; in Alfred and a Markdown file is generated and opened for me to begin work. It’s perfect.  Also, the speed of this site has dramatically increased. It’s a thing of beauty. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re considering switching to Jekyll, I really recommend it. It’s not difficult to dive in, and if you’re a fan of optimized workflows, I think you’ll love how time efficient this process is. If you have any questions, let me know, and I’ll try to answer them.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/tirp-2</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/tirp-2"/>
    <title>The Intellectual Radio Program: Another Unpaid Advertisement</title>
    <published>2013-08-08T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-08-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week: Adam tells the story of going to the Grammy’s, we discuss The Washington Post purchase by Jeff Bezos, and the whole idea of creating an ebook based on something you know and selling it. And of course, we talk through Game of Thrones season 1, episode 3.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/babblenut-2</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/babblenut-2"/>
    <title>Babblenut: I’m in this Brain Dead, Fog, Zombieland</title>
    <published>2013-08-08T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-08-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week: Paul and I talk about self-perception; what it is, how it affects you, and suggestions on what you can do about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;http://blendconf.com&quot;&gt;Blend Conf&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://git-tower.com&quot;&gt;Tower for Mac&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-east-wing-65</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-east-wing-65"/>
    <title>The East Wing: Josh Brewer</title>
    <published>2013-08-06T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-08-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week: I talk with Josh Brewer about his start into design, working at Twitter, trends, and what lies ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;http://blendconf.com&quot;&gt;Blend Conf&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://git-tower.com&quot;&gt;Tower for Mac&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/worlds-first-lab-grown-burger-unveiled</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/worlds-first-lab-grown-burger-unveiled"/>
    <title>World’s First Lab-Grown Burger Unveiled</title>
    <published>2013-08-05T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-08-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The 5-ounce “cultured beef” burger was constructed from 20,000 protein strands grown from cow stem cells. The strands were compiled over the weekend and removed from a deep freezer on Monday. It cost $325,000 to produce, and was financed entirely by Google co-founder Sergey Brin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s one expensive burger.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/tirp-1</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/tirp-1"/>
    <title>The Intellectual Radio Program: Punch You in the Targaryens</title>
    <published>2013-08-02T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-08-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After a month of planning, the first episode of the new show is finally here. What used to be &lt;em&gt;Too Lazy to Blog&lt;/em&gt; has been launched as a new show, called &lt;em&gt;The Intellectual Radio Program&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, we talk about Time Warner pulling a CBS blackout and then reversing their decision, Netflix setting up viewer accounts within a family, and Marco Arment’s post about what having internet fame gets you in terms of sales in the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spend the last half of the show talking through episodes 1 and 2 of Game of Thrones, season 1. Plenty of spoilers abound so you’ve been warned.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/babblenut-1</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/babblenut-1"/>
    <title>Babblenut: There’s Got to Be Something to Fill Those Holes</title>
    <published>2013-08-01T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-08-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;About two months ago, &lt;a href=&quot;http://paularmstrong.me&quot;&gt;Paul Armstrong&lt;/a&gt; and I decided we should do a topical show together. Paul is charismatic, personal, and down-to-earth, and in my experience, those are qualities that are difficult to find in someone that’s as smart as he is. It&#39;s an honor to do a show with him, and I hope you’ll follow along for the ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ladies and gentlemen, I give you &lt;a href=&quot;http://babblenut.com&quot;&gt;Babblenut&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/company-culture-explained</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/company-culture-explained"/>
    <title>Company Culture, Explained</title>
    <published>2013-07-29T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-07-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Culture is not about the furniture in your office. It is not about how much time you have to spend on feel-good projects. It is not about catered food, expensive social outings, internal chat tools, your ability to travel all over the world, or your never-ending self-congratulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article, beautifully points out the underlying problems of “company culture” these days, which although this piece examines startup culture, really applies to a much larger amount of companies. At least personally, the post describes a lot of the reasons why I’ve stayed far away from the startup scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look. I’m interested in hearing what you think.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-new-bytesize-is-live</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-new-bytesize-is-live"/>
    <title>The New Bytesize is Live</title>
    <published>2013-07-26T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-07-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m so happy to announce that my new show, &lt;a href=&quot;http://bytesizenews.co&quot;&gt;Bytesize&lt;/a&gt;, is live! This new show is a labor of love&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1922:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1922:1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I’ve been working on the format for quite some time, and figuring out how the show was going to work, what I was going to report on, and how I’d make it different —and maybe better— from the other news shows out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective of this show is to update you with the most interesting tech, design, and development news each week, yet only take 5–10 minutes of your time. The broadcast is only one part of the show, since you can receive the news straight to your inbox via the newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always wanted to host a news program, and I’m finally getting my chance. I hope you like the new show, and that it&#39;s useful for you. I’d love to hear what you think. Thank you so much for listening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;

&lt;li id=&quot;fn-1922:1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with all the shows I do.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-1922:1&quot; rev=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-fear-of-saying-no</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-fear-of-saying-no"/>
    <title>The Fear of Saying “No”</title>
    <published>2013-07-25T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-07-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Just say No. Don’t use fluffy, doublespeak language. Just say it.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Deny new requests until you have the time and resources to properly look into them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve all been there once or twice. The moment when you feel the scope on a project or sprint creeping up. You feel annoyed, but you worry that saying no might get you fired, or ruin a client relationship. This is a good read, check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-east-wing-shirts-on-sale</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-east-wing-shirts-on-sale"/>
    <title>The East Wing Shirts on Sale</title>
    <published>2013-07-24T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-07-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I completely forgot to mention on this week’s show, that shirts for The East Wing are available for pre-order! We’re selling them through Cotton Bureau, and as you may already know, they require a minimum of 25 shirts to be sold to send it to production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a fan of the show, please pre-order a shirt and shared it with your friends, it would mean a lot to me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/css-guidelines-by-harry-roberts</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/css-guidelines-by-harry-roberts"/>
    <title>CSS Guidelines by Harry Roberts</title>
    <published>2013-07-24T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-07-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty awesome guide on writing better CSS. I recently used a lot of these methods in a project, and while I don’t agree with all of them, I’ve seen how awesome it can be to take CSS organization to a whole other level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, together with a system I’ve recently implemented, has made my CSS a lot more modular and easier to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-east-wing-63</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-east-wing-63"/>
    <title>The East Wing: Chris Coyier</title>
    <published>2013-07-23T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-07-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week: I talk with Chris Coyier about his successful Kickstarter project, going full-time with CodePen, building websites with what you know, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;http://blendconf.com&quot;&gt;Blend Conference&lt;/a&gt; - Use code ‘eastwing’ at checkout for 20% off.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-east-wing-62</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-east-wing-62"/>
    <title>The East Wing: Jim Dalrymple</title>
    <published>2013-07-16T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-07-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week: I talk with Jim Dalrymple about his beginnings, the new Logic, the future of Apple, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;http://blendconf.com&quot;&gt;Blend Conference&lt;/a&gt;. Use ‘eastwing’ when you register for 20% off.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-east-wing-gets-a-redesign</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-east-wing-gets-a-redesign"/>
    <title>The East Wing Gets a Redesign</title>
    <published>2013-07-07T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-07-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m so happy to let you know that The East Wing received a new coat of paint. For those of you interested in learning how I did this redesign, I made it all into a &lt;a href=&quot;http://timlikestoteach.com/courses/redesign-a-podcast-website/&quot;&gt;Tim Likes to Teach course&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What Has Changed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a quite a few problems I had with the old site, and I feel like these have been addressed with this new design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No More Truncated Titles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A lot of people complained about the truncated titles. I totally agree with this, and in fact, I’ve completely changed the episode naming convention to just the name of the guest. Before, I was trying to do a clever title, but I felt it just wasn’t working with the type of show The East Wing is. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better Typography&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I didn’t really like the type of the previous site. In some cases, I felt it was too big, and often overpowering. The new type is so much nicer, and works well on the whole site, instead of just the episode pages like the previous design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emphasis on the Guest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The old design had a picture of the guest on the index page. This new design also has the picture on the episode page. It’s a small detail, but I like the fact that you can always associate the voice with a face.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Back-end Capabilities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Like I’ve said before, when redesigning a site like this, it’s so important to improve the publishing workflow. I created a new custom post type for the new &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net/offair&quot;&gt;Off Air&lt;/a&gt; show, and added an easy way to link each Off Air episode with its corresponding East Wing episode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better Forms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In the past, the forms on the &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;Sponsorship&lt;/a&gt; pages were created from some snippets I’d found. &lt;strong&gt;They sucked&lt;/strong&gt;. The forms are now powered by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gravityforms.com&quot;&gt;Gravity Forms&lt;/a&gt; and allow for some awesome features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so proud of this new design, and I hope you like it too. If you listen to the show live, I think you’ll like some new improvements on the front as well. I’d love to hear what you think of the new design.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/being-honest-about-ios-7</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/being-honest-about-ios-7"/>
    <title>Being Honest About iOS 7</title>
    <published>2013-07-02T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-07-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love Apple. I’ve loved Apple for years, but I think it’s time to stop sucking up and defending them on iOS 7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Apple announced iOS 7 at WWDC, there was a lot of —in my opinion— unnecessary and premature backlash. Nobody had used it, and the whole WWDC keynote aftermath, was one of the greatest examples of &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;&gt;#firstworldproblems&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other end of the spectrum, were people whom I greatly respect, yet seemed to be blind to the obvious issues with the new OS.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1596:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1596:1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using iOS 7 for about three weeks now, and I stand by my statement that it’s a great foundation for developers to build on. There are a lot of new interactions which seem logical, and you can feel the attention to detail in some areas. I’m positive that designers and developers are working hard to implement the new look and feel, in a way that works well for their applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the apps made by Apple are extremely rough around the edges, and a lot of the new aesthetics are downright horrible. Accessibility is an issue in many places, and I’m worried to hear the reaction of my color-blind father, whom I spent most of my adolescent life convincing, that Apple was the pinnacle of design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years, iOS has been the best mobile operating system, and the easiest to learn. Babies and the elderly alike, knew how to use it. I fear this is no longer the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder whether my opinion is clouded by human’s natural opposition to change, although I find this highly unlikely.  What’s worse, is that this whole thing has &lt;a href=&quot;/links/apple-applies-for-iwatch-trademark&quot;&gt;made me skeptical&lt;/a&gt; —and I’m sure others as well— on the future of Apple and the quality of its products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My message to Apple is this:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know I love you. I’ve managed to convince most of the people in my life to buy your products, but you can do better than this. You are not the company influenced by the trends of others, you set them. Get your act together, and make the amazing products I know you can make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;

&lt;li id=&quot;fn-1596:1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loving Apple doesn’t mean you have to agree with them on everything, people.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-1596:1&quot; rev=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/h-fj-announce-web-font-service</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/h-fj-announce-web-font-service"/>
    <title>H & FJ Announce Web Font Service</title>
    <published>2013-07-01T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-07-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This has been a long time coming. I look forward to seeing how successful this is for them. I know many people will be excited to use the well-designed typefaces H &amp;amp; FJ make.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/apple-applies-for-iwatch-trademark</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/apple-applies-for-iwatch-trademark"/>
    <title>Apple Applies for iWatch Trademark</title>
    <published>2013-07-01T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-07-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following months of reports about Apple’s upcoming foray into wearable electronics, the company is now seeking to trademark “iWatch” in Japan, reports Bloomberg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is so exciting. I think Tim Cook made it clear that Apple was interested in this space. However, after iOS 7, I’m skeptical on how well this thing will look and work. I really hope Apple proves me wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/a-new-rss-setup</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/a-new-rss-setup"/>
    <title>A New RSS Setup</title>
    <published>2013-06-30T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;July is upon us, and if you forgot to export your feeds out of Google Reader, you have about 6 hours to do it. Come tomorrow, Google Reader will shut down, and an a new era of RSS will begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris and I talked about alternatives on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ssktn.com/tltb/do-we-really-want-to-go-back-to-aol/&quot;&gt;this week’s Too Lazy to Blog&lt;/a&gt;, but at the time, I hadn’t chosen where I’d go. However, I spent yesterday doing some research and I’d love to share my new setup with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Powering the Backend&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are quite a few choices out there at this point. The problem is that the integrations aren’t great. &lt;a href=&quot;http://cloud.feedly.com/&quot;&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt; for example, seems to have a lot of support, but it’s free and I decided early on that I wanted to pay for the service. This way, the likeliness of the service disappearing is smaller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided on &lt;a href=&quot;http://feedwrangler.net/welcome.html&quot;&gt;Feed Wrangler&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve heard some very good things about the service, as well as the developer behind it. Also, it has a pretty cool bookmarklet for you to instantly subscribe to a feed. The UI isn&amp;#8217;t great, but I just need it to power the syncing. I almost never visit the actual site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Apps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d previously been using &lt;a href=&quot;http://reederapp.com/&quot;&gt;Reeder&lt;/a&gt;. However, only their iPhone app integrates with any of these new services, and there’s no word on when exactly the iPad and Mac apps will follow. Personally, I don’t really enjoy reading on my phone or on my Mac, so it was important to find a service that integrated with a great iPad app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.curioustimes.de/mrreader/&quot;&gt;Mr. Reader&lt;/a&gt;. Creepy icon aside, the app is really nice. You can customize the reading experience a lot more than Reeder, and the sharing actually works. It has Readability, Twitter, App.net, and Kippt integration which is perfect for me. If you need more than that, have no fear, the app has many different choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you also need a Mac app, I’m most likely going to go with &lt;a href=&quot;http://readkitapp.com/&quot;&gt;ReadKit&lt;/a&gt;. Again, integrations look great, and the customization of the reading experience is pretty awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I hope that helps. Let me know if you’ve found alternate solutions. I’d love to hear about them. Happy reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/too-lazy-to-blog-25</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/too-lazy-to-blog-25"/>
    <title>Too Lazy to Blog: Do We Really Want to go Back to AOL?</title>
    <published>2013-06-28T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week: Adam is away with a sick household so Tim and Chris hold down the fort and talk through 30/30, a time management app, Google Reader’s imminent death, sidebars and blog design, Discovery asking for more money and is Orphan Black the best show on TV?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re taking a two week break, and we’ll be re-launching the show with an all new name, artwork, and more! Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/my-interview-on-founders-talk</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/my-interview-on-founders-talk"/>
    <title>My Interview on Founders Talk</title>
    <published>2013-06-27T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am so incredibly honored to be on Founders Talk this week. Founders Talk, is one of the first show’s I ever listened to, and a huge inspiration when I created The East Wing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to hear more about my story and projects, you should take a listen.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-east-wing-60</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-east-wing-60"/>
    <title>The East Wing: Getting Serious with Nicole Dominguez</title>
    <published>2013-06-25T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week: I talk with Nicole Dominguez about how she got started in Design, being young, her thoughts on college, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;http://blendconf.com&quot;&gt;Blend Conf&lt;/a&gt;. Use the code ‘east wing’ for 30% off.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-imperfectionist</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-imperfectionist"/>
    <title>Sara Wachter-Boettcher on Embracing Imperfection</title>
    <published>2013-06-24T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But when we only promote our shiniest pieces, we don’t really build confidence. We build shallowness. We start measuring our work in terms of the fame we get out of it, rather than the heart we put into it. We start mistaking praise for progress, and we take projects or jobs that look good on paper (or balance sheets), but do little to help us learn and grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve told Sara she’s one of my favorite writers, and a piece likes this just makes me like her more. I admire writing that is able to expose the true self, and I hope that one day, I can be this vulnerable with my writing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/my-interview-on-pixel-recess</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/my-interview-on-pixel-recess"/>
    <title>My Interview on Pixel Recess</title>
    <published>2013-06-24T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My new friend Paul Armstrong interviewed me on his awesome show. I&#39;m definitely not as funny as his previous guests, but you should definitely take a listen.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/jobs-trailer-finally-out</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/jobs-trailer-finally-out"/>
    <title>Jobs Trailer Finally Out</title>
    <published>2013-06-21T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m so incredibly excited about this. I hope Ashton Kutcher doesn&#39;t disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-east-wing-59</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-east-wing-59"/>
    <title>The East Wing: Write Your Own Thing with Marco Arment</title>
    <published>2013-06-19T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week: I talk with Marco Arment about how he got started, getting the job at Tumblr, Instapaper, The Magazine, and the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;http://blendconf.com&quot;&gt;Blend Conference&lt;/a&gt;. Use ‘eastwing’ at checkout for 30% off.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/tim-likes-to-teach-gets-a-redesign-2</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/tim-likes-to-teach-gets-a-redesign-2"/>
    <title>Tim Likes to Teach Get’s a Redesign</title>
    <published>2013-06-17T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, I launched the new &lt;a href=&quot;http://timlikestoteach.com&quot;&gt;Tim Likes to Teach&lt;/a&gt;. This redesign has been in the works for about three months. Not a huge amount of time, but considering that when I started, it was only supposed to be a minor update, it ended up taking quite a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m very proud of this new design, and if you&amp;#8217;re an existing customer, I think you’re going to love it. The old site had quite a bit of pain points, and I think this new design addresses them very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beauty of this redesign is, I’ve improved the back-end to make it easy to add new courses and videos. I&amp;#8217;m new using a custom post type for courses and course videos, then connecting them with a plugin called &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.org/plugins/posts-to-posts/&quot;&gt;Posts to Posts&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience has greatly improved on the front-end too. In the past, videos were on a page and some couldn’t even find them. &lt;strong&gt;It was totally my fault&lt;/strong&gt;. When I first designed the site, the plan was to have you download all the video files, so the design didn&amp;#8217;t work when that plan didn&amp;#8217;t work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I feel the site has a good flow to it. Breadcrumbs do a good job of helping you remember where you are, and give quick access to the course homepage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A New Course&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As promised, I’ve started to post videos for the new course “Redesign a Podcast Website”. Lots of people have showed interest in this project since there are some interesting design and development problems to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course is currently in progress, and I&amp;#8217;m recording and adding new videos everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A New Business Model&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As most of you know, I&amp;#8217;m now &lt;a href=&quot;http://ttimsmith.com/articles/the-future-of-tim-smith&quot;&gt;full-time on my own projects&lt;/a&gt;, so I&amp;#8217;m looking for ways to generate enough income to sustain myself. With that in mind, Tim Likes to Teach has moved to a subscription model. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For only $8.99/month, you get access to all courses and respective downloads. There is a formal plan for future courses, and I&amp;#8217;m already doing pre-production on these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, I hope you love this new design. As always, my goal remains the same: to help people learn the web with their friendly internet pal, me. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/too-lazy-to-blog-23</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/too-lazy-to-blog-23"/>
    <title>Too Lazy to Blog: Mexican Standoff of Silence</title>
    <published>2013-06-13T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week: We talk through WWDC news &amp;mdash; iOS7, Mac OS X Mavericks and the features and new stuff that we’re excited about. We also talk about the new Superman movie coming out and stare at our analytics.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-east-wing-58</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-east-wing-58"/>
    <title>The East Wing: You Have Your Own IMDB Page with Paul Armstrong</title>
    <published>2013-06-11T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week I talk with Paul Armstrong. Paul is a designer, photographer, film writer, and actor. He has such an interesting mix of skills and talents, and we had the chance to talk about where they intersect, iOS, working on meaningful problems, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;http://slideandstage.com&quot;&gt;Slide and Stage&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net/blendconf&quot;&gt;Blend Conf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/sponsor-blend-conference</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/sponsor-blend-conference"/>
    <title>Sponsor: Blend Conference</title>
    <published>2013-06-07T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m proud to talk about a new sponsor we have over on &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net&quot;&gt;The East Wing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blend Conf is a generalist conference featuring 50 speakers sharing ideas and conversations about user experience design, user interface design, and web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers include folks like: Carl Smith, Jason VanLue, Jina Bolton, Meagan Fisher, and more. I’m very honored to have been asked to speak as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net/blendconf&quot;&gt;Register for Blend Conf&lt;/a&gt; today with promo code “eastwing” and get 30% off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to BlendConf for supporting The East Wing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/too-lazy-to-blog-i-need-my-diapers-now-amazon-mom</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/too-lazy-to-blog-i-need-my-diapers-now-amazon-mom"/>
    <title>Too Lazy to Blog: I Need My Diapers Now Amazon Mom!</title>
    <published>2013-06-06T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week: Chris and I introduce Adam to Game of Thrones, we discuss Netflix losing licensing for Spongebob, the deluge of new iOS mail apps, and the upcoming week of WWDC news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We&#39;re looking for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ssktn.com/sponsorship/&quot;&gt;sponsors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/its-not-that-complicated</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/its-not-that-complicated"/>
    <title>It’s Not That Complicated</title>
    <published>2013-06-05T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I first got into this industry, things were a lot simpler. We didn’t worry about designing responsively, and there were no “mobile strategies”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The iPhone hadn’t even come out yet. My workflow consisted of designing in Photoshop, slicing the design into tons of PNG’s, and coding all of this up in Dreamweaver.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1511:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1511:1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m glad we’ve come so far in the past years. I feel like we’ve collectively improved the web a lot. People involved in web projects are thinking about process, strategy, user experience, and a whole lot more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, for graduating students, or anyone else barely entering our industry, I can see how it could seem overwhelming. Every day, there seems to be a new technology we should be learning, or articles explaining something we’re not paying attention to. Job postings don’t really help. A lot of these postings use big words, and the whole hiring process can be very intimidating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone who’s been in his fair share of interviews, don’t let these intimidate you. Every time I started a new job, I’d get nervous that I wouldn’t be able to do it. Yet, I’ve learned that the web can be complicated, but if you’re hard working and eager to learn, everything else can be taught.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you’re feeling stressed, take a break. Think about something else. When you get back, try your best. That’s really the only thing you can be asked for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;

&lt;li id=&quot;fn-1511:1&quot;&gt;
Thankfully, I never made anything with tables. Although, it does give some type of street cred to say you did.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-1511:1&quot; rev=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/overcoming-yourself</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/overcoming-yourself"/>
    <title>Overcoming Yourself</title>
    <published>2013-06-03T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Writing for me, is one of those things I wish I could be great at. I can read pieces by other people, and be moved, inspired, motivated, and more with a single paragraph. Great writers are able to convey emotion and tell a story while keeping you interested with every word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For as long as I can remember, I&#39;ve told myself that I can&#39;t write. I&#39;ve noticed that I have the power to hold myself back, if I don&#39;t fight against the urge to talk myself out of things. If I want to be a great writer, what better way than to practice a little everyday?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That’s exactly what I’m doing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m tired of telling myself I can&#39;t do something; that&#39;s the world&#39;s job. I can&#39;t draw, I can&#39;t play piano, I can&#39;t be fit, etc; it&#39;s rubbish. I can do all those things. The only thing in the way is &lt;strong&gt;me&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s quite an interesting moment when you realize the biggest hurdle to overcome is your own cynicism; that&#39;s ridiculous. If anything, you should be rooting for your own self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I give up on trying to stop myself from doing something I really want; you could be on the edge of greatness and not realize it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/tltb21</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/tltb21"/>
    <title>Too Lazy to Blog: We Don’t Know About the UK</title>
    <published>2013-05-31T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week, Myke Hurley fills in for Adam to talk Tim Cook’s apperance at D11, Apple buying rights to sports broadcasts, Marco selling The Magazine, and the HTC One release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We&#39;re looking for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ssktn.com/sponsorship/&quot;&gt;sponsors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/on-redesigns</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/on-redesigns"/>
    <title>On Redesigns</title>
    <published>2013-05-31T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What is the point of redesigning something? What&#39;s trying to be accomplished? Whether it be an app, website, or any type of product, clear goals are behind necessary redesigns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When clients have come to me in the past to redesign their website or brand, the first question out of my mouth, is why. Often, people have an idea of what they&#39;re trying to accomplish:  they want more customers, they&#39;d like to provide current users with a better experience, they&#39;d like to create a future-friendly website, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Redesigning for the sake of change is limited to personal sites. This should never be a strategy where the user experience is actually important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As designers, it&#39;s necessary we think these things through. Too many people believe that design is purely visual, and sometimes, we contribute to that incorrect assumption. The reality is, design is heavily reliant on asking the right questions, and properly analyzing the answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we do this, we can create designs that improve an experience, and possibly improve the lives of our users.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/part-two-with-adam-stac</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/part-two-with-adam-stac"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Adam Stacoviak</title>
    <published>2013-05-30T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week, I had the chance to talk with my friend Adam Stacoviak. Adam is a Designer, Developer, and Broadcaster. We talked about building products. They&#39;re not easy to create or maintain, and sometimes you have to make tough decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Episode sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;http://slideandstage.com&quot;&gt;Slide and Stage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/make-your-own-club</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/make-your-own-club"/>
    <title>Make Your Own Club</title>
    <published>2013-05-30T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve never felt like I belong to a club. In school, I wasn&#39;t popular, I didn&#39;t play sports, nor was I a good student. I didn&#39;t really fit in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most of my school years, it bothered me. I became a person I wasn&#39;t, just to be accepted. It wasn&#39;t until the final years of high school that I realized I could just be myself, and not care. I could find friends who liked me for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a certain way, this type of thing continues in work and on the web. The popular people and the ones who aren&#39;t. Unlike high school, the popular kids are mostly really nice. However, I&#39;ve noticed that I —and many others— continue wanting to be part of the club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is “the club” anyways?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we sometimes forget is that there are lots of clubs, and being active on the web is as easy as reaching out. If you don&#39;t seem to find one that suits you, make one. Create a place where you feel comfortable and can be edifying to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being friends with big names isn&#39;t what makes you awesome, being kind and respectful does. You can&#39;t give people too much importance; sometimes, even your heroes will let you down. Time spent resenting is time not spent on doing great work.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/tim-cook-at-d11</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/tim-cook-at-d11"/>
    <title>Tim Cook at D11</title>
    <published>2013-05-29T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This interview in a lot of ways is ridiculous. Walt and Kara went a bit to the extreme in trying not to show any bias towards Apple, and instead were a bit harsh. Although, I can understand how difficult it must be to conduct an objective and unbiased interview with the CEO of arguably the best technology company at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tim seems very confident in Apple and it&#39;s future, and why wouldn&#39;t he? Their stock price has nothing to do with the success Apple has reached, nor does it say anything about the legacy they&#39;ve already created for themselves. Anyone who follows Apple knows that they&#39;re working on something big, and their silence only guarantees that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More about this on tomorrow&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ssktn.com/category/tltb/&quot;&gt;Too Lazy to Blog&lt;/a&gt;. Catch us &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ssktn.com/live&quot;&gt;live&lt;/a&gt; at 3pm Central Time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/i-dont-know-what-im-doing</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/i-dont-know-what-im-doing"/>
    <title>I Don’t Know What I’m Doing</title>
    <published>2013-05-29T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a phrase I’m getting into the habit of saying more. It&#39;s completely true, and the more I say it, the more benefit I seem to get out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know why, but as humans, we like to give the illusion of having knowledge; whether it be true or not. I know I do. I love making people feel like I know what&#39;s going on and how to handle a situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I don’t.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I’ve tried to be more open about the things I don&#39;t know and I&#39;ve been very happy with the results. The great part of admitting ones shortcomings, is the opportunity it creates for learning. You’d be amazed how willing people are to give help and advice. It&#39;s my belief that with a little humility, and a willingness to learn, there is nothing you can&#39;t accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are you admitting to not knowing today?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/the-future-of-tim-smith</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/the-future-of-tim-smith"/>
    <title>The Future of Tim Smith</title>
    <published>2013-05-28T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve quit my job and stopped looking for full-time work. What&#39;s next for me then?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I&#39;ve explained in a &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/dealing-with-insecurities&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, the past year has been quite the journey. I moved across the country, worked with some great people, and made some bad choices. However, this post isn&#39;t about reflecting on the past; I&#39;ve done enough of that. I&#39;m done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of you may know that I recently quit my job at &lt;a href=&quot;http://rocketlift.com&quot;&gt;Rocket Lift&lt;/a&gt;. I can&#39;t send enough love to those guys. They are hands down the best team I&#39;ve worked with so far, and there was seldom a day when I wasn&#39;t excited to get to work.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1447:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1447:1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first inclination was to find another full-time job. I applied in a couple of different places that I was interested in, some didn&#39;t get back to me, and a few interviewed me. After this whole process, I realized that there&#39;s really only one company I&#39;d actually like to work for, and that&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://lift.gs&quot;&gt;Lift&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lift&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1447:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1447:2&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is a great company that’s working on some very exciting things. I feel like I could learn a lot and I know &lt;a href=&quot;http://chris-wallace.com&quot;&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt; likes that I have all these side-projects. If there was ever a good fit for me, I think it’d be there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, since they’re not offering a position at the moment, I stepped back and questioned why I was looking for a full-time job in the first place. I&#39;m single.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1447:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1447:3&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I have no family to support. Why work full-time, make tons of money, yet not have the ability to freely work on my side-projects, when these are what bring me joy? That&#39;s when it hit me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…I’d rather be poor and do something I love than make lots of money doing something I don’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People spend a lifetime stuck in a routine they hate. They wake up at the crack of dawn, sit in traffic, work for 8 or 10 hours, come home, and start all over again. I don&#39;t want this for myself. Ever. Life was created to be enjoyed, and that doesn&#39;t sound like joy to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, if there is a position that I feel will be good for me and these projects, I’ll take it. Till now, most of the companies I’ve interviewed with had no knowlege of my side projects&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1447:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1447:4&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, nor did they show any interest in them. For me, this is a huge red flag, and one of the reasons I’ve turned down some offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My projects are important to me, and what these employers don’t realize, is that these ventures make me a better employee, and in some cases, bring attention to their companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What I&#39;m Doing Instead&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know I have the skill and talent to create things people love, and will be willing to pay for. More importantly, I&#39;m fortunate to have people who like what I do, and want to support my endeavors. The plan is to make the things I&#39;m already doing profitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consulting Work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m a great Designer and Front-End Developer. At the moment I&#39;m taking clients for the next couple of months. If you, or someone you know, needs a designer, please &lt;a href=&quot;/portfolio&quot;&gt;take a look at my portfolio&lt;/a&gt;. You can also &lt;a href=&quot;http://zerply.com/ttimsmith/endorse&quot;&gt;read what others have said about me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The East Wing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This show is special to me. It&#39;s definitely my favorite project to work on. However, it needs to become more profitable. Each month, we attract around 20k people. That means we should be able to sell sponsorships at a higher rate. I&#39;ve also created &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net/membership&quot;&gt;memberships&lt;/a&gt; for the show. If you love the show, and you kinda-sorta like me, please consider becoming a member. These memberships help pay me for the time I put into it, and honestly, will help me pay my rent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lustra Magazine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ll be submitting &lt;a href=&quot;http://lustramag.com/&quot;&gt;Lustra&lt;/a&gt; to the App Store at the beginning of June; that&#39;s a hard deadline. I&#39;ve completely redesigned the magazine for the iPad, and —not to toot my own horn— it&#39;s looking beautiful. I think you&#39;re really going to like it and if this first issue is a success, I have some exciting plans for the project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tim Likes to Teach&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This project in particular has a lot of untapped potential. A considerable amount of people loved &lt;a href=&quot;http://timlikestoteach.com/&quot;&gt;Tim Likes to Teach&lt;/a&gt;. I&#39;ll be deploying a beautiful new design that improves the experience of the site. It will soon be moving to a subscription where you get access to everything for only $8.99 a month. I have a pretty cool course plan for this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bytesize&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is a new show I plan to do. It&#39;s a weekly news update focused on the tech, design, and development industries. You can &lt;a href=&quot;http://bytesizenews.co/&quot;&gt;sign up for the newsletter&lt;/a&gt; to be notified of when the show launches. This show is part of a bigger plan, that I can&#39;t wait to show you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&#39;s the plan; make a living from the projects I currently have, and more that I won&#39;t talk about yet. If you&#39;re interested in supporting me, and this plan, consider &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net/membership&quot;&gt;becoming a member&lt;/a&gt; on The East Wing. It&#39;s inexpensive, and the more support it gets, the less I&#39;ll have to worry about sponsorships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to reiterate that I have no idea what I’m doing. Who knows? Maybe I’ll have to end up taking a job to make my bills. I really hope not. I think these things have the potential to earn me a living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much, without you, this wouldn’t even be a possibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;

&lt;li id=&quot;fn-1447:1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know you&#39;ve suffered with a case of the Mondays before.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-1447:1&quot; rev=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li id=&quot;fn-1447:2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it me or do I seem to like companies with the word &quot;Lift&quot; in it?&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-1447:2&quot; rev=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li id=&quot;fn-1447:3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d really like to make a joke here, but it&#39;d probably be misinterpreted in text.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-1447:3&quot; rev=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li id=&quot;fn-1447:4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&#39;re on my resume. It&#39;s impossible to miss.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-1447:4&quot; rev=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/instacast-for-mac-is-out-of-beta</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/instacast-for-mac-is-out-of-beta"/>
    <title>Instacast for Mac is Out of Beta</title>
    <published>2013-05-28T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll be honest, only recently was I recommended Instacast by my friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://mykehurley.net/&quot;&gt;Myke Hurley&lt;/a&gt;. This app has changed the way I consume shows. For me, the ability to have show notes, cloud syncing, and a simple and easy to use Mac App, has made the whole Instacast experience one I can recommend whole-heartedly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re like me, I&#39;d gotten so frustrated with the bloat of iTunes and now with Instacast for Mac, I&#39;ll never have to open iTunes ever again (hopefully). I&#39;ve been beta testing the app for a couple of weeks now, and I made sure to purchase a license now that it&#39;s out of beta. It&#39;s currently on sale for $14.99 until May 31st.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should totally &lt;a href=&quot;http://vemedio.com/store&quot;&gt;buy a copy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-adam-clark</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-adam-clark"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Adam Clark</title>
    <published>2013-05-21T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week I talk with Adam Clark. Adam is a developer and superb podcaster. We talk about how he got into the web, taking risks in business, and starting his first podcast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;http://slideandstage.com&quot;&gt;Slide + Stage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-ashley-baxter</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-ashley-baxter"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Ashley Baxter</title>
    <published>2013-05-17T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week, I had the opportunity to talk with Ashley Baxter. Ashley describes herself as a tinkerer of many things, and I agree. At a young age, she took over the family business and has branched out into other products. We talk about how she got started, her first talk, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;http://slideandstage.com&quot;&gt;Slide + Stage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/videos/become-a-better-designer-with-side-projects</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/videos/become-a-better-designer-with-side-projects"/>
    <title>Become a Better Designer with Side Projects</title>
    <published>2013-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a talk I gave back in April at &lt;a href=&quot;http://minnestar.org/minnebar&quot;&gt;Minnebar&lt;/a&gt;. As many of you know, I have a couple of side projects, and I wanted to help other people see the benefit of these. You can see the slides &lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/ttimsmith/become-a-better-designer-with-side-projects\&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/the-future-of-lustra-magazine</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/the-future-of-lustra-magazine"/>
    <title>The Future of Lustra Magazine</title>
    <published>2013-05-13T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I regret to inform you that I&#39;m killing it… nah, I&#39;m just kidding. Who writes a post about killing something and calls it &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.adobe.com/fireworks/2013/05/the-future-of-adobe-fireworks.html&quot;&gt;The Future of…&lt;/a&gt;? Idiots. This post is not about the death of &lt;a href=&quot;http://lustramag.com/&quot;&gt;Lustra&lt;/a&gt;. In fact, it&#39;s about its rebirth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lustra has been quite the journey. It started off as a horrible &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/timothybsmith/make-awesome-magazine&quot;&gt;Kickstarter campaign&lt;/a&gt; that failed, was rebranded as Lustra, and then left alone as I slowly lost passion for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past few months have been tough. We didn&#39;t get nearly as much sponsorship support as I&#39;d hoped, and the cost of printing and shipping was a lot larger than what we had in the bank. We were stuck between a rock and hard place. We couldn&#39;t print the thing, yet had used some of the sponsorship towards costs relating to the magazine. I was stressed, and the project had become the bain of my existence.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1408:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1408:1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this was going through my mind, and I couldn&#39;t figure out a way to quit. I was torn. I wanted to quit, but I didn&#39;t want to, nor could I. Then, yesterday, while sipping on a strawberry lemonade &amp;mdash; I recommend one if you&#39;re having brain blockage &amp;mdash; the lightbulb came on. I&#39;d design the magazine as an iPad only magazine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2013/05/lustra-demo-jason.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jason&#39;s Design for People Article&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The magazine will come out as a single-issue app in the App Store. I know this will limit the amount of people that can have access, however the pros outweigh the cons at the moment. We&#39;ll be able to publish the magazine under budget, I won&#39;t have to worry about shipping and fulfillment, and I&#39;ll be able to design the reading experience beautifully. Lustra will be one of the few design magazines that looks great on the iPad.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1408:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1408:2&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2013/05/lustra-demo-paddy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Paddy&#39;s Act Article&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions, or want to tell me you love this idea, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ttimsmith&quot;&gt;you know where to reach me&lt;/a&gt;. You can subscribe to the newsletter &lt;a href=&quot;http://lustramag.com&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;

&lt;li id=&quot;fn-1408:1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to read a great post on completing things because you absolutely have to, you should &lt;a href=&quot;http://daneden.me/2013/04/unfinished-business/&quot;&gt;read this by Dan Eden&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-1408:1&quot; rev=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li id=&quot;fn-1408:2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m looking at you .net Magazine.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-1408:2&quot; rev=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-too-lazy-to-blog</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-too-lazy-to-blog"/>
    <title>New Episode of Too Lazy to Blog</title>
    <published>2013-05-09T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week, on Too Lazy to Blog, we discuss the weather, future of Adobe Creative Cloud, iOS 7 design hopes, Abercrombie &amp;amp; Fitch, low end cell phones and Jim Dalrymple’s Loop magazine and the Type Engine that powers it.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-matt-steele</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-matt-steele"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Matt Steele</title>
    <published>2013-05-07T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week I had the chance to talk with my friend, Matt Steele. Matt has an inspiring story with difficulties and successes. Personally, these are some of my favorite interviews to do; when you can relate with the journey of a person.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-dan-benjamin</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-dan-benjamin"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Dan Benjamin</title>
    <published>2013-05-02T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week, I had the awesome chance to talk with Dan Benjamin. We did the show live, and it was so much fun. We talk about him freelancing back in the days, radio, and the future of internet broadcasting.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/dealing-with-insecurities</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/dealing-with-insecurities"/>
    <title>Dealing with Insecurities</title>
    <published>2013-04-29T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not one to suffer of low self-confidence much, but like everyone else, I have my moments. And this is one of them. I&#39;m insecure; I&#39;m scared; I&#39;m worried.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past eight months have been interesting. I left a great job for more money somewhere else, and was subsequently fired. I made personal decisions that hurt my family, and those who love me. To say the least, when I felt that everything was going well, the rug was pulled from under me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve suffered the consequences of these bad decisions, yet grown in ways I couldn&#39;t have imagined. I&#39;ve become confident with the person I am, proud of the person I&#39;ve become, and am becoming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve become a person that thinks about saving money. A person that doesn’t take decisions motivated by greed, but instead with humility and a goal to keep things simple. Someone who understands that my decisions affect others, and to think otherwise is selfish. And what real love is, and how what you do says so much more than anything you could possibly say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I deal with the feelings of regret everyday. Why did I let money cloud my good judgement? Why do I miss that company so much when they don’t seem to miss me at all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also feel like one day, someone’s going to figure out I’m a complete fraud. Someone’s going to find out that I don’t really know what I’m doing, that my code sucks, or that there’s really nothing special about the design work I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years ago, I thought these feelings of regret and fraud would go away. That a day comes when you don&#39;t care what anyone else says or thinks, you just produce great work, and you&#39;re happy. That one day, you don’t seek the validation of others. You don’t care about web traffic, or the praise and/or acceptance of your heroes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out that, this doesn’t just happen. You have to work at it. As silly as it seems, I’ve had to actively remind myself not to care. I’m constantly having to tell myself that my mistakes don&#39;t define me, they inform the person I am. I&#39;ve had to force myself not to think of the &quot;what-ifs&quot; in life, but to accept that the past cannot be changed, and that the only way to look is forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;However,&lt;/strong&gt; there are moments, where all of these things, that I know to be logically true, go out the window, and we end up where I started this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are moments when, even though I portray to know what I&#39;m doing, I really don&#39;t. I have no freaking idea. I&#39;m winging it, and waiting for people to find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job search makes these feelings even stronger. Was I right to quit? Do I just have a huge ego? What if I end up under a bridge somewhere?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So what happens next?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is, I don’t know how to “cure” these feelings. What I do know, is that they won’t stop me. There’s no point in allowing yourself to grow stagnent, you have to keep moving forward, and pushing your own boundaries. Sometimes that’s really scary, but I always think that if it’s not scary, you’re not doing something right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vulnerability is frightening, and most people find it to be a weakness. I disagree. Being vulnerable —those moments when you lay everything you’ve got on the table— is when you can truly grow and become a better version of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll continue to deal with insecurities, but they won’t be calling the shots.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-sam-kapila</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-sam-kapila"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Sam Kapila</title>
    <published>2013-04-24T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week, I had the pleasure of talking with Sam Kapila. Sam is a Designer and Educator, and from what I can tell, one of the first people to teach Responsive Web Design at a University level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I know that Responsive get&#39;s thrown around a lot as a buzz word, but Sam is working with &lt;a href=&quot;http://happycog.com/&quot;&gt;Happy Cog&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://paravelinc.com/&quot;&gt;Paravel&lt;/a&gt; as her unofficial advisory board. It&#39;s great to see the support she&#39;s received in Austin for teaching her students the right stuff, and I had a blast talking with her.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-josh-long</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-josh-long"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Josh Long</title>
    <published>2013-04-17T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week I had the chance to talk with Josh Long. Poor Josh had to talk with me twice since I forgot to record the first time. Since Josh is a total pro, we did a take two and the conversation was even better.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/launching-the-new-rocket-lift</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/launching-the-new-rocket-lift"/>
    <title>Launching the New Rocket Lift</title>
    <published>2013-04-11T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is an exciting day at Rocket Lift. We&#39;ve been working very hard to get this new site up. I&#39;m really proud of the work I did, and the team did. I think it&#39;ll propel Rocket Lift to a new level, and show to potential clients, the company that we actually are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read more about the redesign &lt;a href=&quot;http://rocketlift.com/design-ux/giving-rocket-lift-a-facelift/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/stop-working-so-hard</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/stop-working-so-hard"/>
    <title>Stop Working (So Hard)</title>
    <published>2013-04-08T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What did The Hustle™ accomplish? I gained weight. I wasn’t spending enough time with my (now) wife. I felt like shit. I began to resent my work, and the work I was producing clearly wasn’t my best. I started cutting corners. I went from a mindset of shipping with quality and integrity to “when is this going to be over?”&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;[…]&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;If your colleagues, clients, or bosses don’t get why working less is a better idea, leave. There are far better places to be than at a company that values quantity over quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I absolutely love articles like this. Actually, I love people who think like this. It&#39;s been my experience that working a lot, doesn&#39;t mean you&#39;re producing a lot. Over time, I&#39;ve tried to work smart, and try to get more done in a smaller amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article hits home a bit closer today as I try to loose weight. Two years have gone by, and I&#39;ve gained 100 lbs. Why? Because I was so focused on work, I forgot that it&#39;s only the means to live my life; &lt;strong&gt;not the reason&lt;/strong&gt; to live life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven&#39;t, you &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/i-m-h-o/ef4772e3c628&quot; title=&quot;Link to Stop working (so hard)&quot;&gt;should read the original article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-jory-raphael</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-jory-raphael"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Jory Raphael</title>
    <published>2013-04-03T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week, I had the chance to talk with Jory Raphael. This is a guy that I just loved talking to. He&#39;s so talented and successful, but also a down-to-earth guy. We talk about his inspiration behind the 5by5 artwork, how he got his start, and a brilliant app that he&#39;s a co-founder of. I think you&#39;ll love this episode.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/good-copy-is-more-valuable-than-design</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/good-copy-is-more-valuable-than-design"/>
    <title>Good Copy *Isn't* More Valuable than Design…</title>
    <published>2013-04-02T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Think about the design portfolios you see on dribbble and around the web. They’re sleek, intuitive, beautiful…. and they all sorta look the same. They don’t tell you how they helped solve a problem, they just show you the hi-res designs of their solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, I don&#39;t like the title of this post. However, it was probably meant to get people interested in the topic, &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/silicon-valley-can-suck-it&quot;&gt;something I&#39;ve done before&lt;/a&gt;, so I&#39;ll let that slide. For a designer, I almost feel like the writer doesn&#39;t value the role of his own job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copy &lt;em&gt;is not&lt;/em&gt; more valuable than design. They are equally important on the web. Without great copy, design fails to do it&#39;s job, and likewise, without great design, it doesn&#39;t matter how great your copy is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the most part, however, I agree with a lot of what he&#39;s saying. As designers, we should be good with words. After all, we are responsible for the presentation and effectiveness of a given message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://robertwilliams.wpengine.com/warning-startups-need-good-copy-more-then-design/&quot;&gt;Read it&lt;/a&gt;, see if you like it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/looking-back-march-2013</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/looking-back-march-2013"/>
    <title>Looking Back: March 2013</title>
    <published>2013-03-31T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;March has gone by in what seems like a blink of an eye. This is what I&#39;ve been up to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, I&#39;d like to give a shout-out to my pal &lt;a href=&quot;http://matt-steele.com&quot;&gt;Matt Steele&lt;/a&gt; whom gave me this idea. He writes a post at the end of every month, I assume in an effort to document things. Here&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://matt-steele.com/blog/single/march-2013-in-review&quot;&gt;the one he wrote for March&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Launching Tim Likes to Teach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of March, I was so excited to &lt;a href=&quot;/links/my-first-product-launches&quot;&gt;launch my first product&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://timlikestoteach.com&quot;&gt;Tim Likes to Teach&lt;/a&gt; is a place for anyone to learn Web Design, Front-End Development, WordPress, SCSS, Compass, and so much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I launched with one course called &lt;a href=&quot;http://timlikestoteach.com/courses/design-and-build-an-art-directed-blog/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design and Build an Art-Directed Blog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which is priced at $8. I priced it low on purpose. I wanted as many people as possible to have the ability to purchase it; whether you want to learn a new skill, you&#39;re considering a career change, or you&#39;re a kid who&#39;s only money comes from an allowance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The East Wing Nominated for an Award&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is huge for me. I&#39;ve never been nominated for anything before, so that y&#39;all thought my show was worthy of this honor is very humbling. It&#39;s interesting to see a project which I started more for myself without any intentions of popularity or praise, garnering such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether I win or lose, I love doing that show, and I can&#39;t thank those of you who listen enough for all the support and kindness you&#39;ve shown me. It&#39;s a pleasure doing that show, and I hope to do it for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve listened to the show, and you like it, I&#39;d love to have your &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thenetawards.com/&quot;&gt;vote&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;New Shows&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m also currently working on new shows. I can&#39;t say much about them at the moment but, I&#39;m really excited to be planning them. I&#39;ve had these ideas for quite some time, but I finally feel like I have the time (or I&#39;ll make it), and that I can make them a success; more news on this soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&#39;s it. March has been a busy month and it looks like April will be too. Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-young-guns-show-with-trevan-hetzel</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-young-guns-show-with-trevan-hetzel"/>
    <title>New Episode of the Young Guns Show with Trevan Hetzel</title>
    <published>2013-03-28T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My pal &lt;a href=&quot;http://galengidman.com/&quot;&gt;Galen Gidman&lt;/a&gt; launched the redesign to his podcast, the Young Guns Show. I&#39;m so excited to see him producing shows again. If you&#39;re a young person in this industry, and even if you&#39;re not, I&#39;m sure you&#39;ll like this podcast. It&#39;ll inspire you to get your butt into gear and get stuff done.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/launching-version-6</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/launching-version-6"/>
    <title>Launching Version 6</title>
    <published>2013-03-25T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Early last week, I launched version six of this site. I honestly don&#39;t know if that version number is correct, because in the early days, I redesigned this site a lot more than I do now; I was sixteen, and procrastinating on my homework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing has changed, now I just procrastinate on work. Ha!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this redesign is a huge one. If you browse the site, you won&#39;t see huge content changes. The portfolio is the same, the about page as well. The biggest content change takes place on the contact page with the new form. I&#39;m using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gravityforms.com/&quot;&gt;Gravity Forms&lt;/a&gt; to power it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The form is using conditional logic, and displays different inputs based on what you&#39;re contacting me for. I&#39;m hoping that this new form makes it easy for people to get in touch, and encourages people to just say hello. I like getting those types of emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll notice that this new form also has a speaking engagements option. This is something I&#39;m very interested in pursuing, and again, I hope this new form will facilitate that conversation with conference organizers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Under the Hood&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I&#39;ve tried to make it very easy to update the content on this site. I noticed that I came across a lot of links that I wanted to share a bit more &quot;permanently&quot; than just on Twitter. I also noticed that I didn&#39;t always have time to flesh out an article, but I wanted to add my thoughts to them. The link and video post formats have been perfect for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A huge pain point was the portfolio section. In the past, I&#39;d gotten lots of criticism from potential employers for not having a portfolio. With NDA&#39;s, designs not being used, or only participating on parts of projects, I didn&#39;t really have much to show. Plus, I wasn&#39;t to keen on showing the early crap I had done on my own. Finally, while working at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lullabot.com/&quot;&gt;Lullabot&lt;/a&gt;, I was able to lead two projects that I was very proud of and I created my portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the front end, it looked beautiful. I received some very nice compliments of my work and the way I chose to display them. However, on the back end, I was using pages for all of it. Essentially, I had pages nested within pages in WordPress. I had to hack it together, and if I did something incorrectly, the whole thing would break. Plus, I was using a whole bunch of custom fields, and it was just getting out of hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided it was time to conquer my fear of custom post types and get this done. Now, I&#39;m using a custom post type for the portfolio and Advanced Custom Fields together, and everything is running smoothly and efficiently. If you don&#39;t know about custom post types, you should sign up for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://timlikestoteach.com/&quot;&gt;Tim Likes to Teach Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;. I&#39;ll be covering it in the next course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last pain point was the about page. You&#39;ll notice that this page contains a list of my interviews and published articles. In the previous version, this was a page template that had been hard coded. Meaning that every time I wanted to add a new article or interview, I had to open up the file, add a new list item, git commit, and push.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m now using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.advancedcustomfields.com/add-ons/repeater-field/&quot;&gt;repeater field&lt;/a&gt; to handle this. I&#39;ve created fields for the name of the interview or article, the publishing date, and where it was published, and Advanced Custom Fields and Wordpress takes care of the rest. Easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Wrapping Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s the rundown of the new site. If some of these concepts are new and or difficult for you, please sign up for the Tim Likes to Teach Newsletter. I promise to explain them in an easy way. The docs can sometimes be difficult to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please take a look around, have a cookie, and let me know what you think.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-jen-simmons</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-jen-simmons"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Jen Simmons</title>
    <published>2013-03-21T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week on The East Wing, I had the chance to talk with Jen Simmons. I&#39;m a huge fan of Jen&#39;s podcast, The Web Ahead. I didn&#39;t tell her this, but she was one of the inspirations behind me starting The East Wing in the first place. We talked about how she got started, the work that goes into her podcast, and a lot more.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/empathy-starts-with-vulnerability</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/empathy-starts-with-vulnerability"/>
    <title>Empathy Starts with Vulnerability</title>
    <published>2013-03-21T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ve distanced myself from past projects; I’ve avoided pushing for the sort of work I really want; I’ve glossed over details to avoid admitting how little I actually know. I’ve worked hard, terribly hard, to make my checklist add up to a good job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is such a great thought on The Pastry Box Project by Sara Wachter-Boettcher. I just love her writing. Not to mention, it&#39;s incredibly helpful to see someone you admire have a lot of the same nervousness and insecurity with their work. It reminds us that we&#39;re all human, and that to a certain extent, we all feel we&#39;re figuring it out as we go.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/celebrate-your-achievements</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/celebrate-your-achievements"/>
    <title>Celebrate Your Achievements</title>
    <published>2013-03-19T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just the other day, I noticed that I had been nominated for an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thenetawards.com/&quot;&gt;award&lt;/a&gt;. I was nominated alongside some amazing side projects, and quite honestly, I think I have no chance of actually winning. I was hesitant at first to even tell anyone I had been nominated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net&quot;&gt;The East Wing&lt;/a&gt;, the objective wasn&#39;t to win awards. My only mission is to sit down and create a show better than the week before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve come to conclusion, however, that it&#39;s really important to celebrate achievements in life. Even being nominated for something like this is huge. Life has a way of bringing you down, and if you don&#39;t stop to look at the things you&#39;re doing well, it can get pretty depressing. I feel like we focus on how to improve so much, that we can forget about all the awesome we&#39;re already accomplishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was raised to be humble; to never brag. My belief is that humility is a necessary quality in life. I don&#39;t feel this means we shouldn&#39;t celebrate our achievements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past six months have been some of the worst of my short life; completely because of my poor decisions. The next six months are going to be better. There&#39;s little to nothing I can do about the past, so I&#39;m going to allow myself to be proud of the good things I&#39;m accomplishing and more importantly who I am as a person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Celebrate your achievements people. Take yourself out somewhere nice. Oh… and pictures, or it didn&#39;t happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d like to vote for the .net awards, you can do so &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thenetawards.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-rachel-shillcock</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-rachel-shillcock"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Rachel Shillcock</title>
    <published>2013-03-13T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week on The East Wing, I had the absolute pleasure of talking with Rachel Shillcock. She&#39;s such an awesome gal, and talking with her was so easy since we Skype every once in a while. I&#39;m sure you&#39;ll like the episode; it&#39;s cheerful, happy, and educational.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-geri-coady</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-geri-coady"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Geri Coady</title>
    <published>2013-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week on The East Wing, I had the honor of talking with Geri Coady. Geri is a talend Designer, Illustrator, and Photographer. I&#39;m &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; jealous of her awesome illustration skills. We talk about how she got started, her venture into freelancing, and her process into choosing colors.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/my-first-product-launches</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/my-first-product-launches"/>
    <title>My First Product Launches</title>
    <published>2013-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was an exciting day for me. I launched my first product. I might add, that I took my own advice and charged for it from the beginning, which is something I&#39;m also very excited about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been working hard for a couple of months to create an introductory course for &lt;a href=&quot;http://timlikestoteach.com/&quot;&gt;Tim Likes To Teach&lt;/a&gt;. When I say introductory, I don&#39;t mean in skill level. It&#39;s introductory in the sense that it will acquaint you with the site, the type of content and perks that come with each course. This course is a six-part series that spans more than six hours of content. It covers best practices in HTML, CSS and more. We cover the markup necessary for the design, yet we also talk about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; we mark it up in that way. At least in my experience, that has so much value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the future, I&#39;ll be creating other courses. You might have heard that one of these will feature a complete redesign of &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net/&quot;&gt;The East Wing&lt;/a&gt;. I hope you&#39;ll subscribe to the newsletter so you&#39;re always in the know of the latest course. To those of you who purchased the first series, or if you plan to, my sincerest of thank you&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is something you&#39;d like to learn about, I hope you&#39;ll let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/videos/the-making-of-john-mayers-born-raised-artwork</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/videos/the-making-of-john-mayers-born-raised-artwork"/>
    <title>The Making of John Mayer’s ‘Born &amp; Raised’ Artwork</title>
    <published>2013-03-01T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I found this video via &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jasonvanlue&quot;&gt;Jason VanLue&lt;/a&gt;. The attention to detail is amazing. I envy the talent of people like this.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/interview-on-show-me-your-mic</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/interview-on-show-me-your-mic"/>
    <title>Interview on Show Me Your Mic</title>
    <published>2013-02-28T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2013-02-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, I was asked to be on Show Me Your Mic. It&#39;s a podcast that talks to other podcasters about their setup and the story behind the shows. For me, it&#39;s a lot of fun because we talk about so much more than gear (which in my case isn&#39;t the coolest setup ever). If you&#39;re interested in podcasting or want to start a podcast of your own, I&#39;m sure you&#39;ll like this show.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/videos/deploy-securely-with-sftp</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/videos/deploy-securely-with-sftp"/>
    <title>Deploy Securely with SFTP</title>
    <published>2013-02-27T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2013-02-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the past, I&#39;ve had issues with using SFTP. For some reason, the documentation I had looked at, didn&#39;t really help. So I decided to make a quick screencast on using SFTP to deploy files to your server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you liked this screencast, you might like &lt;a href=&quot;http://timlikestoteach.com/&quot;&gt;timlikestoteach.com&lt;/a&gt;! Learn web design, front-end development, WordPress, Scss, and more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Video Notes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/matro&quot;&gt;൱αϯr๏ (matro) on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-elliot-jay-stocks</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-elliot-jay-stocks"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Elliot Jay Stocks</title>
    <published>2013-02-20T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2013-02-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was looking forward to this episode so much. As you may know, I&#39;m trying to publish a magazine. Elliot has successfully published five issues of one. In this episode, we talk about how he got started, his first job, and much more!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/the-coffee-shop-hypothesis</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/the-coffee-shop-hypothesis"/>
    <title>The Coffee Shop Hypothesis</title>
    <published>2013-02-19T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2013-02-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, I decided to leave my home office and work at the local coffee shop. This is the second time in the past two weeks that I&#39;ve done this and I&#39;ve come to a realization: although I spend less time working, I&#39;m producing more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like working remote but, in recent months, being away from the family, I&#39;ve noticed that my love for it has decreased. I don&#39;t see many people during the day and it feels kind of blue. But, I&#39;ve noticed that the days I go out to the coffee shop or make a lunch plans, are much better days for me. I produce more and generally feel happier about the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you felt something similar? Do you work from a co-working place? A coffee shop? Or do you like only working from home?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/interview-on-podcast-champion</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/interview-on-podcast-champion"/>
    <title>Interview on Podcast Champion</title>
    <published>2013-02-19T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2013-02-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This past week, I was so excited to be interviewed on Podcast Champion: a podcast by my pal Justin about podcasting. It was a lot of fun to talk about why I started The East Wing, what&#39;s impact it&#39;s had in my life and a lot of the behind-the-scenes work that goes into producing the show. If you&#39;re like me, curious about that type of stuff, I&#39;m sure you&#39;ll like this podcast.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-sara-wachter-boettcher</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-sara-wachter-boettcher"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Sara Wachter-Boettcher</title>
    <published>2013-02-14T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2013-02-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week on The East Wing, I had the absolute pleasure of talking with Sara Wachter-Boettcher. Sara is a Content Strategist, Author of &lt;a href=&quot;http://rosenfeldmedia.com/books/content-everywhere/&quot;&gt;Content Everywhere&lt;/a&gt;, Editor of &lt;a href=&quot;http://alistapart.com&quot;&gt;A List Apart&lt;/a&gt;, speaker, and a down-to-earth gal. I had the chance to ask her about content strategy and where it fits within the process of making a website, writing a book, the editorial process at A List Apart, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/my-article-on-the-branch</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/my-article-on-the-branch"/>
    <title>My Article on The Branch</title>
    <published>2013-02-12T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2013-02-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Inspiration is not only the way you think; it&#39;s why you think that way. It&#39;s a feeling. It&#39;s the feeling you get before you work on something for hours. For me, it&#39;s the moment I know I&#39;ll need a fresh cup of coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago, I was asked by James, the Editor of The Branch, to write an article about this simple question: What inspires you? I&#39;ve always had a difficult time responding to that question but, I feel the article does a good job of exploring what my answer is. Hope you find my thoughts useful.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/me-on-the-page-break-podcast</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/me-on-the-page-break-podcast"/>
    <title>Me on the Pagebreak Podcast</title>
    <published>2013-02-12T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2013-02-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You might’ve noticed that I published an &lt;a href=&quot;http://timothybsmith.com/links/my-article-on-the-treehouse-blog&quot;&gt;article on the Treehouse Blog&lt;/a&gt; about business. My friends over at Pagebreak invited me to be on their show and talk about it. I’m usually having to worry about everything working properly during a recording but, this time, all I had to do was show up. It was so fun!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-laura-kalbag</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-laura-kalbag"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Laura Kalbag</title>
    <published>2013-02-08T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2013-02-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had the delight of talking with Laura Kalbag on The East Wing this week. She&#39;s a Designer and Front-End Developer and absolutely awesome. We talked about how she got started, equality in our industry, mentorship and so much more.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/videos/putting-back-the-face-into-typeface</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/videos/putting-back-the-face-into-typeface"/>
    <title>Putting Back the Face into Typeface</title>
    <published>2013-02-06T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2013-02-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is such a wonderful interview with Erik Spiekermann. The more I hear him, the more I like him. He seems like such a nice guy with a true passion for design.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-trevan-hetzel</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-trevan-hetzel"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Trevan Hetzel</title>
    <published>2013-01-30T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2013-01-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week on The East Wing, I talk to the young and very talented Trevan Hetzel. We talked about how he got started, growing his business in a rural area and his soon-to-be-launched product, Sidecar.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-andy-clarke</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-andy-clarke"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Andy Clarke</title>
    <published>2013-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2013-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week I had the absolute pleasure of talking with Andy Clarke. He&#39;s written two great books and given talks at many conferences. We had the chance to talk about his books, podcasts and dealing with clients properly.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/my-article-on-the-treehouse-blog</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/my-article-on-the-treehouse-blog"/>
    <title>My Article on the Treehouse Blog</title>
    <published>2013-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2013-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Freelancing is regarded as the holy grail in our industry. It’s something most people look to as a magical fantasy land where all dreams come true. However, being a freelancer can be very difficult if you don’t know much about the business of design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a month ago, my buddie Josh Long asked if anyone was interested in contributing to the Treehouse blog. Since I have a constant need to feel &amp;amp; sound smart, I jumped at the chance! Today, my first article went live. I talk about some things I&#39;ve picked up related to the business of design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/make-awesome-is-now-lustra-magazine</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/make-awesome-is-now-lustra-magazine"/>
    <title>Make Awesome is Now Lustra Magazine</title>
    <published>2013-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2013-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m so very pleased to let you all know that Make Awesome is now Lustra Magazine. If you recall, back in October I launched a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/timothybsmith/make-awesome-magazine&quot;&gt;Kickstarter project&lt;/a&gt; to fund this magazine. I did a horrible video, priced the magazine too high and the project was unsuccessfully funded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I noticed that people loved the idea; they loved the idea of a magazine about people making great things. It is the magazine for and about the underdogs; the people that don&#39;t always get the spotlight they deserve. This is definitely a message I could identify with and many others too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I decided to keep this idea going.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lots of internal debate, I decided to rename the magazine Lustra. In Spanish, the word &quot;lustre&quot; means to give polish or shine. I felt that this word resonated with the mission I was on with this publication. I changed a letter so it would be a bit easier to pronounce in English and bam! Lustra Magazine was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m really excited about what&#39;s coming and we&#39;re very close to confirming the fourth and final interviewee for this issue. I&#39;d like to give a huge thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://jarederondu.com/&quot;&gt;Jared Erondu&lt;/a&gt; for assuring me that I had chosen a great new name and for all the help he&#39;s given me throughout this project. I&#39;d also like to give thanks to everyone who&#39;s been following along, for your support and kind words. I appreciate it so much.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-trent-walton</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-trent-walton"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Trent Walton</title>
    <published>2013-01-16T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2013-01-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week on The East Wing, I had a chance to talk with Trent Walton. Trent is the guy behind the awesome art directed articles on his &lt;a href=&quot;http://trentwalton.com&quot;&gt;personal site&lt;/a&gt; and is one-third of &lt;a href=&quot;http://paravelinc.com/&quot;&gt;Paravel&lt;/a&gt;. He&#39;s a really great guy and it was nice chatting about how he got into design and the early troubles of Paravel.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-steve-sam</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-steve-sam"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Steve &amp; Sam</title>
    <published>2013-01-09T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2013-01-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, I had the chance to sit down with Steve Derico and Sam Soffes. These two guys are behind one of my favorite podcasts: &lt;a href=&quot;http://refactor.tv/&quot;&gt;Refactor.Tv&lt;/a&gt;. In the episode we talk about a variety of things. It was really fun to record. It feels more like you get to listen in to one of our conversations more than an actual interview. </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/my-definition-of-success</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/my-definition-of-success"/>
    <title>My Definition of Success</title>
    <published>2013-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2013-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s 2013. Another year has come and gone in what seems to be a blink of an eye. For me, it&#39;s been a bittersweet year full of mistakes and achievements. As I look back on 2012, I will forever remember it and its many ups and downs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, with a new year, comes a feeling of excitement; a feeling of starting anew, where we all begin at zero and where we have the hope to set and reach new goals. At least for me, the goals seem to be the same for every year: lose weight, get up earlier, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&#39;ve had the time to think a lot about these goals and my life. My first reaction was to get upset and angry at myself for not accomplishing these seemingly simple goals. Yet, I&#39;ve come to the realization that keeping hope and not giving up on these things are in and of itself a feat. I&#39;ve realized that the effort says as much and maybe more about a person than the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s only normal to think the other way though. We&#39;ve grown up in a society that measures results; whether it be money, statistics or championships. What about the hard work behind these results? And the work of those that didn&#39;t reach them? Are their efforts of any less value? What about us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It makes no sense to measure our results by someone else&#39;s definition of success&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past year has been rough for me. I&#39;ve made bad personal decisions, I quit a job that I loved and was fired from the one I quit for. I was left with no savings, a new apartment lease and a hefty car payment. All while being more than 1,600 miles away from my family in a place where below zero temperatures are normal during the winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a while I was content with saying my life sucked and calling it a day. That&#39;s no longer the case. It goes against my nature to be this way. I&#39;m an optimist and I know that things always find a way to work out. But, you&#39;ve got to put in the work. I refuse to be of the people that are only happy when success is handed to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that said, here are my goals for this year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lose Weight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Like I&#39;ve said before, this is something I&#39;ve been trying to do forever. I need to eat more vegetables, fruit and less sweets. I just got myself a gym membership too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pay Attention to the Relationships that Matter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I love my family. I love my friends. I need to spend more time with them. At the end of the day, these are the things that make you happy and that really matter in life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speak on Design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;d really like to speak more in 2013. I did one talk at my local meet up last year and it went great. I&#39;d be a great speaker for any event. Don&#39;t believe me? &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net&quot;&gt;Listen to my podcast&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work Less&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
For many, this might seem like a dumb goal if you&#39;re trying to be successful but, again, who&#39;s definition are we measuring it to? I&#39;d like to work just enough to pay my bills and use the rest of my time for other important things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel More&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m single and in the prime of my life. I need to get out of my apartment more and get back to exploring the world one cup of coffee at a time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So these are the goals I hope to accomplish in 2013. If I don&#39;t accomplish them all, there&#39;s always 2014. The point is to never give up on your goals, nor on yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about you? What do you want to accomplish?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/sharing-is-caring</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/sharing-is-caring"/>
    <title>Sharing is Caring</title>
    <published>2012-12-27T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-12-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, I’ve been making an effort to have coffee or meet up with fellow designers and developers here in the Twin Cities. We have a very strong community of smart and creative people here so, I&#39;ve been trying to get to know people individually. As you might know, I’m a coffee addict so, these meetings are a great way to feed the vice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I’ve come across something extraordinary. In each of these coffee meetings, we always end up talking about something fascinating that the other person is working on and my question is always the same: “Why aren’t you writing about this?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve realized that way too many people are shy about writing or documenting about their process and work. Interestingly, I talked about this with &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net/episodes/37-brian&quot;&gt;Brian Hoff on The East Wing&lt;/a&gt; the other day. We talked about how helpful it was for him to start &lt;a href=&quot;http://thedesigncubicle.com/&quot;&gt;The Design Cubicle&lt;/a&gt;. That blog has not only been a huge source of work for him; it&#39;s served countless times as a valuable resource for me and likely for many of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would’ve happened if he hadn’t been keen on sharing? I think it&#39;s safe to say that his career would be completely different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you another story. I had the pleasure of going to &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontenddesignconference.com/2012&quot;&gt;The Front-End Design Conference&lt;/a&gt; last June. Both &lt;a href=&quot;http://daverupert.com/&quot;&gt;Dave Rupert&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://darcyclarke.me/&quot;&gt;Darcy Clarke&lt;/a&gt; clearly admonished people to share and blog more about what they were working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I completely agree with this movement.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be thinking, “Another blog? Would anyone even be interested in what I write?”. &lt;strong&gt;That doesn&#39;t matter.&lt;/strong&gt; Let me give you a couple of reasons why you should be writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn as you go&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Do you think Chris Coyier knew what he was doing when he first started &lt;a href=&quot;http://css-tricks.com/&quot;&gt;CSS-Tricks&lt;/a&gt;? I bet you he didn’t. He was fascinated with what you could do with CSS and just wanted to share what he was learning along the way. In the process, he went from being a beginner to a very respected person in our industry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Most of the work I’ve done, whether it be freelance or the full-time jobs I’ve been so fortunate to hold, have come about either through this blog or &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net/&quot;&gt;The East Wing&lt;/a&gt;. Employers and clients like people who are passionate about what they do and sharing things you’re learning is a great way to show that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strengthen Your Personal Brand&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A lot of people want to write for the big blogs or publications to be recognized but, what they’re forgetting is their own brand. I think a great example of this &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/&quot;&gt;John Gruber&lt;/a&gt;. You know him from his own personal writing place: Daring Fireball, not as the writer from another publication. He’s turned his name and brand into a very respected one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do you say? Will you throw embarrassment or the thoughts of not having enough experience to the wind and start your own blog? Will you start sharing what you’re working on and help others who may be trying to learn something similar?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-brian-hoff</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-brian-hoff"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Brian Hoff</title>
    <published>2012-12-26T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-12-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had the huge pleasure of sitting down with Brian Hoff last week on The East Wing. We got to talk about how he started, some very sound business advice and a whole lot more.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/wunderlist-2-is-gorgeous</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/wunderlist-2-is-gorgeous"/>
    <title>Wunderlist 2 is Gorgeous</title>
    <published>2012-12-25T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-12-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Wunderlist is here to help you get things done. Whether you&#39;re planning an overseas adventure, sharing a shopping list with a loved one or simply keeping track of your daily to-dos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier last week, 6Wunderkinder released the new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.6wunderkinder.com/wunderlist&quot;&gt;Wunderlist 2&lt;/a&gt;. I had never used any of their products before but, I&#39;m so glad I finally did. Wunderlist 2 is an amazingly well-made app. The polish and simplicity is great and as you&#39;d expect, you can reach your lists and to-do&#39;s from anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you, like me, like to keep track of the things you need to get done and love gorgeous UI&#39;s, you need to get your hands on Wunderlist 2.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/special-2012-end-of-the-year-address</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/special-2012-end-of-the-year-address"/>
    <title>Special 2012 End of the Year Address</title>
    <published>2012-12-20T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-12-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll be honest, I loved the &lt;a href=&quot;http://5by5.tv/specials/10&quot;&gt;State of the Union Address&lt;/a&gt; that Dan Benjamin did on 5by5. It was so personal and I think that&#39;s why so many people love Dan. I had been thinking of doing something similar to thank everyone listening to The East Wing in our first year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&#39;t believe how quick these past 10 months have gone and the huge support we&#39;ve received. For me, a person that doesn&#39;t have thousands of followers, it&#39;s amazed me to see the number of listeners rapidly increase every week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net/episodes/2012-eya&quot;&gt;take a listen&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;ll take two minutes of your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;You can read the transcript &lt;a href=&quot;http://onword.co/2074&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/shoptalk-show-with-me</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/shoptalk-show-with-me"/>
    <title>ShopTalk Show with Me</title>
    <published>2012-12-19T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-12-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was so honored to be on &lt;a href=&quot;http://shoptalkshow.com/&quot;&gt;ShopTalk Show&lt;/a&gt; last week! It was such a blast recording with Chris and Dave. We talk about the weeks hot drama, what&#39;s going on with Make Awesome and more!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-kerem-suer</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-kerem-suer"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Kerem Suer</title>
    <published>2012-12-19T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-12-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I got the awesome pleasure of talking with &lt;a href=&quot;http://kerem.co/&quot;&gt;Kerem Suer&lt;/a&gt; this week on The East Wing. He&#39;s such a smart and talented guy and we got to talk about college, his work at Fitbit and more.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-drew-wilson</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-drew-wilson"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Drew Wilson</title>
    <published>2012-12-06T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-12-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve long been a fan of &lt;a href=&quot;http://drewwilson.com/&quot;&gt;Drew Wilson&lt;/a&gt;. He&#39;s a real down-to-earth guy that does tons of awesome stuff. Not only do I like a lot of things he does, I like the reason why he does it.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/a-better-toy-for-developing-girls</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/a-better-toy-for-developing-girls"/>
    <title>A Better Toy for Developing Girls</title>
    <published>2012-12-05T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-12-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s always bothered me that girls are brought up thinking they’re princesses. I feel like it’s a huge lie. Being a princess isn’t an actual job you can achieve and isn’t real life. The truth is, women don’t dress up in gowns everyday and “Prince Charming” only exists in books. Girls can grow up to be so much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/goldieblox&quot;&gt;Debbie Lewis&lt;/a&gt; knows this and wanted to create a toy that would stimulate an interest in science and engineering for girls. It&#39;s called GoldieBlox. I admire what she’s doing and I’m glad she’s doing it. Find out more about the toy &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.upworthy.com/move-over-barbie-8212-youre-obsolete&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/latest-news-updates</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/latest-news-updates"/>
    <title>Latest News &amp; Updates</title>
    <published>2012-12-04T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-12-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d like to start off by announcing that as of yesterday I started as the Director of Design for &lt;a href=&quot;http://rocketlift.com&quot;&gt;Rocket Lift Inc&lt;/a&gt;. I&#39;ve been working on client projects with these guys for about two months now and I&#39;ve come to really like them. They&#39;re a fun team, we say things that HR reps have nightmares about and we have big plans of what we&#39;d like to do together. Also, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/mattepp&quot;&gt;Matt Eppelsheimer&lt;/a&gt; is very well aware of my other projects and is giving me time to work on them and for that, I&#39;m very thankful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the upcoming months, I&#39;m looking forward to the projects we have in the pipeline and also being part of positioning ourselves to do some really exciting things with WordPress. We&#39;re overhauling the branding of the company and the website will receive a much needed re-design. Again, I can&#39;t tell you how excited I am to be part of all this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The East Wing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My podcast continues strong and I&#39;m amazed that I&#39;ll be publishing episode thirty-five this week. I&#39;ve had an amazing year with the show. I&#39;ve talked to some very smart people, people whom I&#39;ve been following for years and can now call friends. Stay tuned for full update a on The East Wing coming out in the next couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Make Awesome&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, thank you to the many who supported and backed this project with their hard earned money. I&#39;m so thankful to you. The Kickstarter campaign did fail but, it&#39;s not the end of this idea. I&#39;m currently talking to companies interested in sponsoring the magazine and I&#39;ve found a local printer who will print the magazine for a significantly lower price. This is great for two reasons. First, the reduced cost will make the magazine affordable for more people and second, we&#39;ll be able to say the magazine was created in Minnesota. We have such an amazing community here and it&#39;ll be exciting to see one more thing that was completely made here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, in the next couple of weeks, Make Awesome will resurface with an all new name. I&#39;m renaming the magazine because a very popular designer, Leslie Jensen-Inman, had started doing things under &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.makeawesomeness.com/&quot;&gt;Make Awesomeness&lt;/a&gt;. I had no idea of this when I named the magazine. Since we haven&#39;t published an issue yet, I want to change the name in good faith and not interfere with anything she might be doing. What&#39;s the new name? You&#39;ll have to &lt;a href=&quot;http://makeaweso.me/&quot;&gt;subscribe to the newsletter&lt;/a&gt; to find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Browser Tap&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a project I&#39;m very excited about. &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/craigcondon&quot;&gt;Craig Condon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/tim_erickson&quot;&gt;Tim Erickson&lt;/a&gt; and myself have been working on an app that will make cross-browser testing so much easier than it is right now. We&#39;ve rethought the way it&#39;s done and hopefully made an application that will fit into your workflow instead of you having to accommodate to an application. Craig is a genius and has been doing some amazing things from the technical side. We hope to start sending out beta invites very soon. If you want to stay updated, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/browsertap&quot;&gt;follow @browsertap&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;So Much More&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite honestly, there is so much more I&#39;m planning on doing. &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/mattsteeele&quot;&gt;Matt Steele&lt;/a&gt; will tell you. I want to get more involved here in the Twin Cities community. Maybe organize a meet up. Maybe even a conference. The days of me sitting around and seeing other people do all this awesome stuff are gone. I want to do things I have a passion for. I&#39;m going to make stuff because I want to see it exist and I&#39;m going to have fun doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end of this year puts an end to an extremely bittersweet time. I&#39;ve made great decisions and horrible ones; some of which I&#39;ll regret for a very long time. But, life isn&#39;t about sulking about the things that happen to you or the stupid things you decide to do, it&#39;s about learning, moving on and making things better. 2013 is my year.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-chris-wallace</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-chris-wallace"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Chris Wallace</title>
    <published>2012-11-28T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-11-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week on The East Wing, I had the pleasure of recording with Chris Wallace. He&#39;s a real down-to-earth guy that has gone through a lot in life and never gives up. I admire him a bunch and it was fun hearing more about his story and the exciting things he&#39;s working on.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/instantbight-interview</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/instantbight-interview"/>
    <title>InstantBight Interview</title>
    <published>2012-11-27T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-11-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, I received an awesome email from David Silverman, a ninth grader that has interviewed some of the best in our industry on InstantBight. How I made it on that list, I don&#39;t know. However, I&#39;m very happy and honored to be on it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/connecting-less</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/connecting-less"/>
    <title>Connecting Less</title>
    <published>2012-11-23T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-11-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I started an experiment today. I removed email from my phone. This isn&#39;t a huge deal but, I&#39;m going to try it for a whole week and see where I&#39;m at after that. I decided to do this because I feel to plugged in all the time. I&#39;m constantly worrying if a client has sent me something I should get to or if someone has sent me a message offering me a lot of money (haha yea right).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The problem&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was watching Parks and Recreation (you should watch it too if you&#39;re not) the other day and I noticed that even though I had finished work, I was constantly checking my email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve noticed that ever since I started freelancing, I respect my personal time less. I&#39;m always on and I hate that. At least for me, I&#39;m not liking the unbalanced balance I&#39;m striking here. As much as my clients might not like it, I shouldn&#39;t be available past 5pm Central Time. Anything that happens after that can wait till the next morning. Of course, there are some exceptions but for the most part, it can wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll always remember something my Dad tells me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You&#39;ve got to look out for yourself because no one else is going to do it for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As sad as that is, it&#39;s true. If people know they can get you to do things for free, they will. If they know you&#39;re reachable at night for “project emergencies”, they will take advantage of that. Of course, I think it&#39;s essential to be respectful when establishing these limits and I&#39;ve seen that when I set them early, things go so much smoother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in an effort to keep the balance a bit better and enjoy life more, I&#39;m eliminating email from my phone. In the world we live in, with everything being instant and people becoming less patient, I think it&#39;s important to disconnect and enjoy the things away from the desk.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/anythin-goes-business-cards</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/anythin-goes-business-cards"/>
    <title>Anythin’ Goes Business Cards</title>
    <published>2012-11-15T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-11-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2012/11/biz-cards1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Anythin&#39; Goes Business Cards&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may know, the amazing &lt;a href=&quot;http://vicbell.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Vic Bell&lt;/a&gt; did the logo for my new company &lt;a href=&quot;http://anythingo.es&quot;&gt;Anythin’ Goes&lt;/a&gt;. Anythin’ Goes is my small one-man design studio specializing in web and iOS design. I had some business cards made by the awesome people at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.moo.com/share/jmsrc5&quot;&gt;Moo&lt;/a&gt; to hand out to people in an effort to look as professional as possible. I hope it works.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-jeff-sheldon</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-jeff-sheldon"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Jeff Sheldon</title>
    <published>2012-11-14T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-11-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had the pleasure of having Jeff Sheldon on The East Wing this week. For those of you who don&#39;t know, Jeff Sheldon is the Founder of &lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.ugmonk.com/&quot;&gt;Ugmonk&lt;/a&gt;. It was a lot of fun talking to him and seeing how much he&#39;s enjoying running Ugmonk. His story is an interesting one and he imparts some great advice.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/how-do-you-find-freelance-work</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/how-do-you-find-freelance-work"/>
    <title>How Do You Find Freelance Work?</title>
    <published>2012-11-13T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-11-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey freelancers! How do you go about generating leads for freelance projects or finding new projects? So many people say, “Ah.. you&#39;ll get there”, when that’s not really an answer. Thanks for all your help!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/videos/jason-santa-maria-on-saying-no</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/videos/jason-santa-maria-on-saying-no"/>
    <title>Jason Santa Maria on Saying No</title>
    <published>2012-11-12T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-11-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is an amazing talk by &lt;a href=&quot;http://jasonsantamaria.com/&quot;&gt;Jason Santa Maria&lt;/a&gt; on saying no. His reasoning is sound and it&#39;s the type of video that inspires you again about what you&#39;re doing and the decisions you&#39;re making.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-adam-stacoviak</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-adam-stacoviak"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Adam Stacoviak</title>
    <published>2012-11-08T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-11-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recorded a new episode of The East Wing this week with &lt;a href=&quot;http://adamstacoviak.com/&quot;&gt;Adam Stacoviak&lt;/a&gt;. For those of you who don&#39;t know him, he&#39;s a really nice guy. He host three podcasts himself and on the show we talk about podcasting and his role as Product Lead at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.purecharity.com/?aff=36437&quot;&gt;Pure Charity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/freelancing-what-ive-learned</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/freelancing-what-ive-learned"/>
    <title>Freelancing: What I’ve Learned</title>
    <published>2012-11-08T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-11-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been 36 days since I began freelancing again. This time around, it&#39;s going a lot smoother and I&#39;ve seen the practicality of working at companies and design agencies. I&#39;ve had the privilege of working with some very smart people who thankfully have taken the time to impart some of their wisdom with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many have labeled &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.andyrutledge.com/advice-for-new-freelancers.php&quot;&gt;Andy Rutledge&lt;/a&gt; as a jerk for his advice on freelancing. Although I don&#39;t agree with him completely, I do see the value of his words now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I operate my business day to day, I&#39;m noticing that I&#39;ve become significantly better at a lot of things. However, like with everything, there are aspects that I&#39;m still trying to get better at. This post is to look at the things I feel I&#39;m doing right and others that, well, not so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Shower When You Wake Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sounds like an obvious one but, it&#39;s not. There are some people that shower every other day. For me, I shower everyday. When I worked full-time, I&#39;d always shower at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve seen a huge increase in my productivity when I shower in the mornings. Especially since I work from home, it could become to easy to roll out of bed and immediately sit down at my desk. In contrast, a good shower makes me feel fresh, awake and ready to get to work. I&#39;ve only been doing this recently but, I&#39;ve noticed that when I do, I feel really good about the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Don’t Eat Junk Food&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one I haven&#39;t been doing so well. I&#39;ve noticed an increase in my weight since I began freelancing because I&#39;m not as cautious of the food I&#39;m consuming. Junk food is not only bad for your health but, I&#39;ve noticed that it makes me feel crappy about myself. Low self-esteem is no good for a designer or, therefore, anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&#39;ve made a bigger effort to buy vegetables and fruit. I&#39;m a big fan of apples and oranges which are great for you. Apples have some great antioxidants on the outside and are yummy. Oranges have a good dose of Vitamin C and I&#39;ve noticed that when I make a habit of eating them, I get sick a lot less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Wake Up A Bit Earlier&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another one I haven&#39;t been great at but, getting better. My sleep schedule had me going to sleep at 2am and waking up at 11am (way past McDonalds breakfast. Doh! See last point). What would happen is I&#39;d finish my normal work day around 8 or 9pm. For me this was really bad. I felt tired all the time and even though I was getting up late, I still felt I wasn&#39;t getting enough sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, I decided to always be in bed by 12 and wake up at 8 and it&#39;s made a huge difference. I feel rested and ready to kick the day&#39;s butt. I also get coffee earlier and am suitably caffeinated for my commitments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Better Business Practices&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consult with an accountant!&lt;/strong&gt; Do it! This is one of the biggest mistakes I made last time around. An accountant can help you figure out what type of entity you want to be and the proper procedures around quarterly tax payments. Use something like &lt;a href=&quot;http://outright.com/&quot;&gt;OutRight&lt;/a&gt;. They make it easy to import your account and then categorize your expenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Scope Creep&lt;/strong&gt; I had the tendency to price projects at a flat rate. When you sign a contract for a final payment of $5k, that&#39;s great, until you realize you invested about $6k in time. Bill hourly and make sure the complete scope of the project is in the contract! (Wait, don&#39;t have a contract? Get one!) Make it clear that any work beyond the scope will be billed at the hourly rate and to make sure, get all of those requests in writing so that you can prove they approved this extra work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a Contract&lt;/strong&gt; This is necessary for any freelancer. I whole heartedly agree with &lt;a href=&quot;http://muledesign.com/about/mike-monteiro/&quot;&gt;Mike Monteiro&lt;/a&gt; on this one. When asked when it&#39;s time to get a lawyer he said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you want to stop being a design amateur and be a design professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as my next point will state, having a steady cash flow is one of the hardest things to create. So, with that in mind, I suggest you take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://stuffandnonsense.co.uk/blog/about/contract_killer_the_next_hit/&quot;&gt;Andy Clarke&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; thoughts on this. He wrote up a very good contract that I still use for all of my clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating a Steady Cash Flow&lt;/strong&gt; I talk about this as something I seriously need to get better at. At the moment, I feel like I&#39;m living too tight. As much as I&#39;ve tried to keep my expenses down, I was used to a nice full-time salary. Although some offers do come through, not all of them turn into business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this point, I turn to you. What have you done to make this better? How do you go about saving money?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Wrapping Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I think that&#39;s it for now. There is so much to share but, I think small doses are better. Is there something I missed? Or something you&#39;d like to read more about? Let me know and I&#39;ll do my best to write about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/silicon-valley-can-suck-it</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/silicon-valley-can-suck-it"/>
    <title>Silicon Valley Can Suck It</title>
    <published>2012-11-02T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-11-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You might hear me complain about how much I dislike start ups and the Silicon Valley culture. I seem to tweet about it a lot and I have private conversations with friends about it. I thought I&#39;d write to try and organize my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the reasons I dislike start up culture come down to two things. It&#39;s detached and not personal, and I feel it&#39;s downright douchey most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Detached and Not Personal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my biggest gripe against startups and venture capitalists. It&#39;s very detached. There is a common saying that goes, &quot;It&#39;s not personal, it&#39;s business&quot;. Although I mostly agree with these words, I feel like there needs to be a little bit of a personal element.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too many companies throw the needs of their users away for the money that the guys with big pockets can throw at them. These companies aren&#39;t solving people problems, they&#39;re coming up with ideas that get them funded. It might seem like the same thing, but it&#39;s not. I know that money pays the bills as much as the next guy but the start up culture promotes making billions, not doing what you love and living with what&#39;s necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s amazing to me that people covet having millions of dollars, a downtown loft and private jets. Everything comes at a price and those who live that life are empty, work most of the time, and don&#39;t have meaningful human relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;It&#39;s Downright Douchey&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t care if your buddy is the ex-co-founder of Twitter. Don&#39;t talk to me about pivoting and please don&#39;t tell me your idea is the Facebook &amp;amp; Netflix of mommy blogging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being an entrepreneur used to mean something. Entrepreneurs were innovators. They weren&#39;t content with the way things were and dreamt of new and better ways to do them; it wasn&#39;t something you could just put in your Twitter bio and it certainly didn&#39;t give you license to be a douche.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, I like to make things. Yes, I might not always think about my products all the way through. I may never be rich. But, damn it, I will have had fun. I will have had passion for the things I get involved in and I will love my family and my friends to the death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I invite you to make business personal again. Have fun. Be nice. Do what you love and make sure you have time for the important people in your life. Money makes no one happy and I&#39;m pretty damn sure &quot;pivoting&quot; doesn&#39;t either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.jolieodell.com/2010/10/01/youre-not-an-entrepreneur/&quot;&gt;You&#39;re Not an Entrepreneur&lt;/a&gt; (Via &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mattepp/&quot;&gt;@mattepp&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/videos/adam-braults-talk-from-realtimeconf</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/videos/adam-braults-talk-from-realtimeconf"/>
    <title>Adam Brault’s Talk from RealtimeConf</title>
    <published>2012-11-02T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-11-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Love this talk from RealtimeConf. &lt;a href=&quot;http://adambrault.com/&quot;&gt;Adam Brault&lt;/a&gt; is an awesome guy and I&#39;m so bummed I couldn’t make it this year. Hopefully 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/successful-product-launches</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/successful-product-launches"/>
    <title>Successful Product Launches</title>
    <published>2012-11-01T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-11-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Just like an Olympian can’t know if they’re going to win a medal without actually performing on game day, you can’t know if your product is going to be a success in the market without actually releasing it to the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s a sentence I wholeheartedly agree with. In his article, Joshua goes on to explain information that can be gathered about your product before it launches and I agree with that as well. However, it&#39;s been my experience that people tend to over analyze things. I&#39;ve been on both sides of the spectrum where in one case, too much pre-launch work was being done where we should&#39;ve had a priority to ship, and another where we should&#39;ve waited to launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s difficult to find the balance but, I know there is one. My pal Jared Erondu &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/erondu/status/262010897319481345&quot;&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; the other day that it&#39;s vital to believe in the product your building. There comes a point where I feel a team thinking and re-thinking the different aspects of a product starts to feel like a lack of faith. That&#39;s the moment where you either fire them or, you get out. At least personally, I&#39;d rather start generating income and being paid to improve an already launched product than sit on it for months and realize it&#39;s been headed in the wrong direction.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/my-thoughts-on-insites-the-book</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/my-thoughts-on-insites-the-book"/>
    <title>My Thoughts on Insites: The Book</title>
    <published>2012-10-31T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-10-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2012/10/insites-cover.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Cover of Insites: The Book&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the absolute pleasure of receiving my copy of &lt;em&gt;Insites: The Book&lt;/em&gt; in the mail yesterday. I was excited to take it out of its packaging and delve into what turned out to be some fantastic reading (but, I&#39;ll get to that in a moment).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The care, love and absolute craftsmanship that has gone into creating this beautiful book is outstanding and deserves praise. Not only does the book smell fresh off the press, the stock, and type and imagery within are beautiful. I admire the work that Elliot and Keir have done. It&#39;s a showcase of attention to detail. As someone very interested in the work that goes into creating a print publication, I can&#39;t begin to imagine all the difficult design decisions that were made for this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;On The Inside&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Though their backgrounds are diverse, there&#39;s one trait our contributors all share: the love what they do. From that love springs their trademark craftsmanship and relentless curiosity. Their passion is what we appreciate about their work, and in turn, it&#39;s what we appreciate about them.
  &lt;small&gt;Aarron Walter&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let&#39;s talk about the content. The interviews and spectacular pieces by &lt;a href=&quot;http://aarronwalter.com/&quot;&gt;Aaron Walter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.fictivecameron.com/&quot;&gt;Cameron Koczon&lt;/a&gt; truly resonate with me. The people interviewed are of amazing success and it&#39;s great to read something with such an inspiring and coherent theme. Every single one of these people have chosen to do what they love and to create new things with love. It&#39;s this motivation which has created Brooklyn Beta, A Book Apart, Creative Mornings and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, it engraved in my mind that I should be creating things with this same incentive. As Cameron states in his foreword, it&#39;s the way we add depth to our online community; the way we extend beyond our small avatars and 160-character bios. I for one, am very happy to be part of this group of caring and smart people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven&#39;t already, you should &lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.viewportindustries.com/products/insites-the-book&quot;&gt;order your copy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/a-quote-worth-thinking-about</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/a-quote-worth-thinking-about"/>
    <title>A Quote Worth Thinking About</title>
    <published>2012-10-31T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-10-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Visual design is more than an outlet for the aesthetic you&#39;re into right now.
  &lt;small&gt;Allison House&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This small tweet by Allison really got me thinking about my own work. It merits thinking about because what this quote really asks is if you&#39;re designing according to the goals of the website and the needs of its users or only according to the trend you&#39;re into at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/pre-order-execute-book</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/pre-order-execute-book"/>
    <title>Pre-Order Execute Book</title>
    <published>2012-10-29T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-10-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot to be said for the difference between planning for six months, developing for a year, learning that your users don’t want to pay for something, pivoting, starting over on development, and having your investors clean you out, as opposed to launching an open-ended, simple, and small version of a great product in which users tell you exactly what they’re willing to pay for while they’re already paying you.
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.executebook.com/post/34564768853/there-is-a-lot-to-be-said-for-the-difference&quot;&gt;Execute Book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came across this excerpt from Execute, a book by &lt;a href=&quot;http://drewwilson.com/&quot;&gt;Drew Wilson&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/joshlong&quot;&gt;Josh Long&lt;/a&gt;. I pre-ordered a while back and I highly recommend you do to. I&#39;ve had the chance to talk with Drew and I really admire the guy. He get&#39;s things done without even breaking a sweat; at least that&#39;s how it looks from the outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drew has created several income generating products and make a living from them. I think we&#39;d all love to do the same. &lt;a href=&quot;http://executebook.com/&quot;&gt;Pre-order the book&lt;/a&gt; and maybe some of Drew&#39;s genius will rub off.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-value-of-a-website</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-value-of-a-website"/>
    <title>The Value of a Website</title>
    <published>2012-10-26T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-10-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Your website is not a feature that you can half-ass. Spend some money. Protect your future. A good website works hard for your business. Much harder than many employees can offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What an amazing article by &lt;a href=&quot;http://brianhoff.net/&quot;&gt;Brian Hoff&lt;/a&gt; telling businesses to value the work done by a website. In it, he talks about paying up to $100k for his own site. His examination of how online businesses are flourishing is great and hits you with a reality check. It&#39;s so true, our economy isn&#39;t in the pits, it&#39;s just that business isn&#39;t done the same anymore. You should definitely &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thedesigncubicle.com/2012/10/dear-business-im-scared-for-you/&quot;&gt;read this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/pocket</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/pocket"/>
    <title>Pocket</title>
    <published>2012-10-25T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-10-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Pocket is a “read it later”-style service that allows users to bookmark parts of the webs to be read in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This seems like a pretty awesome app. I had to find out if it integrated with Tweetbot because that&#39;s where I usually save links from. It definitely shows promise. Now a days, I feel like I do most of my reeding from recommendations on Twitter instead of RSS feeds anyway. What do you think? Will you be giving it a shot?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/i-cant-write</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/i-cant-write"/>
    <title>I Can’t Write</title>
    <published>2012-10-25T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-10-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I wish I could. I really do. I wish I could be one of those prolific writers that sit down and pump out a thousand words easily. I can count one piece that I&#39;ve written which has exceeded a thousand words and that might even include homework assignments from high school (did I mention I wasn&#39;t a good student?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do they do it? I&#39;ve heard that some dedicate a time in the day to write. An hour, maybe two where they sit down and write something. My pal &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.jarederondu.com/&quot;&gt;Jared Erondu&lt;/a&gt; used to write 10-20 pieces a day for a blog he founded and is now the Editor of The Industry at the age of 18. He&#39;s half man, half amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it a gene? A natural talent? Can you develop this talent? At least in our industry, I&#39;m always talking to designers and developers who say its essential to write. Not only to develop your thoughts and truly know what you&#39;re feeling, but to also share the work you&#39;re doing. I&#39;ve tried to do some of that myself and I&#39;ve found it very therapeutic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I&#39;m coming to realize that the problem I have with my writing is that I feel no one reads it. Maybe that&#39;s the adjustment I need to make. Why do I care if people read my horrendously written thoughts? That&#39;s something I learned from &lt;a href=&quot;http://daneden.me/&quot;&gt;Dan Eden&lt;/a&gt;. He told me in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net/episodes/29-dan&quot;&gt;recent interview&lt;/a&gt; that he started blogging because of course he wanted to be like Chris Coyier some day, I mean, who doesn&#39;t? But also because it was his playground. Somewhere he could express his thoughts and the latest techniques he was learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, it really nailed home the idea that I should be writing because I want to do it and that&#39;s it. If no one reads, that&#39;s quite alright. It helps me organize my thoughts and ultimately makes me a better designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you&#39;re thinking of starting a blog or you&#39;ve already started one but you&#39;ve abandoned it, I encourage you to keep it up. Share the link in the comments and I&#39;ll be sure to visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this day forward, I&#39;m going to write for one hour each day. Some of these are going to really suck but, I hope you&#39;ll join me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/highlighting-young-and-unknown-creatives</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/highlighting-young-and-unknown-creatives"/>
    <title>Highlighting Young and Unknown Creatives</title>
    <published>2012-10-25T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-10-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been thinking a lot about this recently and I&#39;m writing this in an effort to better explain the project and hopefully convince you more effectively than the video on Kickstarter. The truth is, the video doesn&#39;t do this project justice, but that&#39;s a completely different topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I launched Make Awesome, I had a general and, honestly, vague idea. It was a dream that hadn&#39;t been completely fleshed out yet and three weeks later, I now understand what I want this project to accomplish a lot more than I did when I initially launched it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the project&#39;s inception, I&#39;ve had the privilege of doing some interviews that have helped me create a better vision and I&#39;d like to transmit this idea to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of this magazine is celebrate young and relatively unknown people in our web industry. It aims to not only get you thinking about where our industry is heading and new, creative ways to solve new problems; it invites you to enjoy life and to remember that work is only the tool that allows us to enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d say that the magazine will not only be a design magazine but a lifestyle magazine. One that examines what creatives do outside of work and gives suggestions about getting away from the noise. That&#39;s also the reason why I want the magazine to only be print. I completely agree with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.offscreenmag.com/&quot;&gt;Kai Brach&lt;/a&gt;. We are so attached to our devices and I hope that this magazine serves as a much needed break to relax on the couch, have a freshly brewed cup of coffee and read the inspiring stories of others that, hopefully inspire you to continue working on your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a person that loves what you do and has a passion for doing great work, this is the magazine about you. Our industry needs a publication about and for the regular people: those of us who don&#39;t write books, speak at conferences or interview for big publications. Make Awesome is that publication and the magazine is only the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/timothybsmith/make-awesome-magazine&quot;&gt;Back this project&lt;/a&gt;, share the magazine and share the vision.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-jared-spool</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-jared-spool"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Jared Spool</title>
    <published>2012-10-24T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-10-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had the great pleasure of recording an episode with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jmspool&quot;&gt;Jared Spool&lt;/a&gt; about a week ago. He&#39;s such a nice guy. Turns out, he&#39;s an avid listener of the show! We got the chance to talk about how he thought the internet was a fad, all the work that goes into putting on a conference and much more.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/keeping-your-cool</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/keeping-your-cool"/>
    <title>Keeping Your Cool</title>
    <published>2012-10-24T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-10-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re reading this, you probably know me. If you don&#39;t, read other articles on this site or listen to my &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt;. Don&#39;t worry, I&#39;ll wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, now that you know who I am and a bit of my personality, you&#39;ll agree when I say that I&#39;m a nice guy. I&#39;m the type of person that opens the door for women, keep my elbows off the table and always put my napkin on my lap. I&#39;m nice, well-mannered and respectful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, like everyone else, I get upset. People at times say hurtful things because, hell, they&#39;re on the internet and there is nothing you can do. My pal &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/mattepp&quot;&gt;Matt&lt;/a&gt; told me yesterday that basically “trolls gonna troll” and it&#39;s very true. Some people find satisfaction in bringing other people down and that&#39;s just something you have to deal with in your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Anyway&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of this post is to talk about keeping your cool. There have been times recently where nothing would have made me happier then to go all Mike Tyson up on some people but, it&#39;s not worth it. That&#39;s something I&#39;m very proud to say that my mother taught me. It&#39;s never worth reducing to someone&#39;s level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What has worked for me, is that I always remember that there is a real person on the other side of the screen. Always. I don&#39;t want to be the cause of anyone&#39;s feelings being hurt. This isn&#39;t common but, I&#39;ve chosen not to care about what other people do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will always be nice. When I offer criticism, it will be constructive and with tact. When someone decides to troll, my response will be one filled with respect. This is how we make the web a better place: when we decide to not say anything that we wouldn&#39;t say to someone in person and as I&#39;m sure everyone&#39;s mother said at one point, “If you have nothing nice to say, don&#39;t say anything at all”. Because, honestly, the time spent hurting people could be better spent doing something great yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be nice.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/awesome-clients-can-be-found-anywhere</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/awesome-clients-can-be-found-anywhere"/>
    <title>Awesome Clients Can Be Found Anywhere</title>
    <published>2012-10-19T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-10-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been running my own business for about a month now and, wow, have a learned a ton. However, the invaluable things I&#39;ve learned will come in a later post. I&#39;m here to talk about clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, it seems that everyone wants the high profile clients. People with big ideas, the next great product. I admit that I&#39;m included in that group. I would love to design for &lt;a href=&quot;http://rdio.com&quot;&gt;Rdio&lt;/a&gt; or a product similar to that. However, I made realization today that great clients and exciting work can come from anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m currently working with a client whose business is to sell truck bodies. To the typical person, this would seem like a regular client; maybe not something to get excited about. Yet, I am excited about this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The owner of the business is a blue collar worker who genuinely cares about his business and the quality they can provide for their customers. He understands his business, the needs of the customers and how important it is to have a web presence. He&#39;s open to new ideas and accepts the opinions of the professionals, which in this case, is me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I don&#39;t really know what I want to accomplish with this post; I think it&#39;s to persuade people to give clients the benefit of the doubt and not consider any project to small. For me, this experience was unexpected and I&#39;m so glad I&#39;ve had the chance to work with these people. What about you? Have you ever felt that you had a great unexpected experience with a client?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/dont-be-a-douche-pay-for-quality-stuff</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/dont-be-a-douche-pay-for-quality-stuff"/>
    <title>Don’t Be a Douche. Pay for Quality Stuff</title>
    <published>2012-10-18T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-10-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I know that the title is sensational. I&#39;m hoping that people read this just because they&#39;re offended at it. Still, the point I&#39;d like to make is important. A very &lt;a href=&quot;http://tapbots.com/software/tweetbot/mac/&quot;&gt;quality piece of software&lt;/a&gt; came out today and almost immediately, people began to complain about how they weren&#39;t happy with the price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a discussion that happens often. The value of apps are always being measured and I think, unfortunately, the trend is to sway on the low side. I feel like people don&#39;t realize how much work goes into creating a quality application. Countless hours of work; thinking, discussing UX, refining the design, thinking through interactions and development. We&#39;re not talking a couple of days here; we&#39;re talking months of full-time work. In this case, Tapbots has created Tweetbot for the iPhone, iPad and Mac. Quality products deserve to be paid for and the guys at Tapbots have done an amazing job with this suite of applications. Don&#39;t be a douche. Pay for their stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tapbots.com/software/tweetbot/mac/&quot;&gt;Tweetbot for Mac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-aarron-walter</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-aarron-walter"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Aarron Walter</title>
    <published>2012-10-17T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-10-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had the huge privilege of recording an episode with &lt;a href=&quot;http://aarronwalter.com/&quot;&gt;Aarron Walter&lt;/a&gt;. In case you don&#39;t know, he&#39;s a great designer, speaker and author. I had such a great time talking to him about how he got started, design problems he encountered at MailChimp and a lot of the work and research that went into writing his book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abookapart.com/products/designing-for-emotion&quot;&gt;Designing for Emotion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/videos/an-intro-to-scss</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/videos/an-intro-to-scss"/>
    <title>An Intro to SCSS</title>
    <published>2012-10-16T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-10-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">I&#39;ve been promising this video for a long time and I finally had time to doing it. Hope this helps some of you!

&lt;h3&gt;Show Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;show-notes&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codeschool.com/courses/assembling-sass&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Code School, Assembling Sass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/u/bermonpainter/p/css-pre-processors-stylus-less-sass&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CSS Pre-Processors: Stylus, Less &amp;amp; Sass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net/episodes/26-bermon&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SASSin’ It Up with Bermon Painter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/look-ma-i-own-a-company</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/look-ma-i-own-a-company"/>
    <title>Look Ma! I Own a Company!</title>
    <published>2012-10-11T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-10-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today was the quite the interesting day. I&#39;m officially the owner of Anythin&#39; Goes LLC. I&#39;m a business owner and that freaks me out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Reason Behind the Name&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose Anythin’ Goes because I want it to be the parent company over my different projects. I&#39;m not only doing design work, I host a &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; and soon (hopefully) I&#39;ll be publishing a &lt;a href=&quot;http://makeaweso.me&quot;&gt;magazine&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t know exactly what lies in the future for me or the company but I&#39;m excited to find out and I hope you&#39;ll come along for the ride. I think this is all for the best. I feel like finally things are turning around and I&#39;m headed in a good direction, both in my life and career.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-dan-eden</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-dan-eden"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Dan Eden</title>
    <published>2012-10-10T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-10-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had the privilege of talking with &lt;a href=&quot;http://daneden.me/&quot;&gt;Dan Eden&lt;/a&gt; on The East Wing. He&#39;s a really nice guy. The man has tons of self-started side projects and we go through them one by one. He&#39;s got some very interesting things to say so you should &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net/episodes/29-dan&quot;&gt;take a listen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/videos/creative-mornings-berlin-erik-spiekermann</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/videos/creative-mornings-berlin-erik-spiekermann"/>
    <title>Creative Mornings Berlin: Erik Spiekermann</title>
    <published>2012-10-09T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-10-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://daneden.me/&quot;&gt;Dan Eden&lt;/a&gt;, recommended this video to me and I loved it. Erik is hilariously condescending but, you can tell the man knows what he&#39;s talking about. He gives some interesting insight into type for screens that I found very useful. Pardon for some of the foul language. Pretend you didn’t hear it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/support-make-awesome-on-kickstarter</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/support-make-awesome-on-kickstarter"/>
    <title>Support Make Awesome on Kickstarter! Pretty Please?</title>
    <published>2012-10-08T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-10-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2012/10/kick-lead.png&quot; alt=&quot;Post Lead Image&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m so excited to announce that we launched the Kickstarter campaign for &lt;a href=&quot;http://makeaweso.me&quot;&gt;Make Awesome&lt;/a&gt; today! I&#39;ve shot and reshot the video tons of times and finally I had to just be happy with it. I&#39;ve been doing a lot of behind the scenes work and I&#39;m anxious to see if people believe in the idea as much as I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment, we already have some amazing contributors like &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/higley&quot;&gt;John Higley&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Eecho13084&quot;&gt;Abby Barlok&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Spentacular&quot;&gt;Spencer Hamm&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/jglovier&quot;&gt;Joel Glovier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/eaton&quot;&gt;Jeff Eaton&lt;/a&gt; and more to come. Like I&#39;ve said before, we&#39;ve confirmed three of four interviews with &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/_jannalynn&quot;&gt;Janna Hagan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/vic_bell&quot;&gt;Vic Bell&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/samsoffes&quot;&gt;Sam Soffes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d like more up-to-date info, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/timothybsmith/make-awesome-magazine&quot;&gt;back the project&lt;/a&gt; to get the amazing weekly updates!!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/the-thoughts-of-someone-who-shouldnt-be-awake</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/the-thoughts-of-someone-who-shouldnt-be-awake"/>
    <title>The Thoughts of Someone Who Shouldn’t Be Awake</title>
    <published>2012-10-03T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-10-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been working a lot and very hard on my new freelancing business and the magazine. I have the “letter to the editor” layout finished and the “intro to the interview” layout finished as well. I am so nervous. I wonder if all this work will be in vain. I wonder if this idea will fail. I wonder if I&#39;m the right person to execute this idea. I worry that this could turn into a disaster. I read earlier today a great quote from &lt;a href=&quot;http://jasonsantamaria.com/&quot;&gt;Jason Santa Maria&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://thegreatdiscontent.com/jason-santa-maria&quot;&gt;The Great Discontent&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m sure that I’m romanticizing it as I’m getting older, but when you’re a kid, everything seems possible. When you think about doing something, the time between thinking about doing it and actually doing it is usually very brief. You say, “Hey, what if I do that?” and then you’re doing it. As an adult, you think, “I want to do this thing,” or, “I want to make something.” Then you start gathering resources and devising a plan, but then you get tired because you’re old and want to lay down. There’s something about that childhood idiocy that I often think back on and love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I completely agree with him. As we get older we tend to think a lot more about the decisions we make. Interestingly, for personal things, I&#39;ve always been carefree to the point of making some very bad decisions. With work, however, I&#39;d say that most if not all of my decisions have been conservative. I tend to do things that I&#39;m comfortable with; things I know. It&#39;s because of this that I believe this magazine is so hugely important to me. It&#39;s a risk. A huge risk on my part. I&#39;m hoping for the best but being realistic about the possibility of utter failure. Either way, I&#39;m convinced that something can be learned from this experience. I&#39;ve already learned so much about editorial layout for print and I&#39;m excited at the opportunity to call this product mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe these thoughts belong in my personal journal but, I just want to say to those of you who are thinking of taking risky decisions, do it. Jump in. I was so scared to leave the comfort of a full-time job and yet, here I am, with enough money to eat and to have a roof over my head. Take a risk. Work on what you&#39;ve wanted to do. It&#39;s scary as all hell but, can be immensely rewarding and educational.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/progress-on-make-awesome</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/progress-on-make-awesome"/>
    <title>Progress on Make Awesome</title>
    <published>2012-10-01T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-10-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2012/10/ma1-hero.png&quot; alt=&quot;Layout Preview&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this a quick update on Make Awesome. I&#39;ve started to set deadlines for myself so that I actually start getting things done. My Kickstarter video will be up this week come hell or high water. I&#39;d love to see how much interest there is around the idea. For me, it&#39;d be a dream come true to get this published and in the hands of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve chosen the typefaces for the project, which will be &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bariol.com/&quot;&gt;Bariol&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.myfonts.com/fonts/type-together/skolar/&quot;&gt;Skolar&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://pictos.cc/font/&quot;&gt;Pictos&lt;/a&gt; for the icons. I&#39;ve worked with Skolar before on the web and it&#39;s a beautiful typeface that works very well with extended copy. Bariol is also a beautiful typeface and gives the publication and formal yet casual feel at the same time. Pictos is also a great icon font designed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://drewwilson.com/&quot;&gt;Drew Wilson&lt;/a&gt; that has the style I was going for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d like to see a layout I had worked on, you should &lt;a href=&quot;http://dribbble.com/shots/750642-Progress&quot;&gt;look at this&lt;/a&gt;. I&#39;ve changed the layout of it already but, the color and style is pretty defined. It&#39;s interesting how I&#39;ve been creating online editorial environments for most of my career yet I&#39;ve had to learn how to create one for print. The whole mentality is different. Leave a comment with your thoughts on the layout!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-jared-erondu</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-jared-erondu"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Jared Erondu</title>
    <published>2012-09-26T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-09-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This episode was such a blast to record. &lt;a href=&quot;http://jarederondu.com&quot;&gt;Mr. Erondu&lt;/a&gt; is a class act and it was great to get to know him better and what drives this young man. Doesn&#39;t matter what stage of your career you currently find yourself in, I&#39;m sure you&#39;ll pick up something of value from this episode.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/looking-for-new-opportunities</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/looking-for-new-opportunities"/>
    <title>Looking For New Opportunities</title>
    <published>2012-09-19T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-09-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So as I said earlier today, my time at &lt;a href=&quot;http://andyet.net&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;yet&lt;/a&gt; has ended. I really liked the team and enjoyed my time there but they&#39;re looking for someone that is more developer oriented. In fact, if you&#39;re looking for a front-end position, you should check them out. They&#39;re a great team and I appreciate everything they&#39;ve done for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, I&#39;ll be looking for freelance work or a full-time position. If you know of anything or you have a web project you&#39;d like me to work on, &lt;a href=&quot;/contact&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;! I&#39;d love to talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/my-article-on-the-students-guide-to-web-design</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/my-article-on-the-students-guide-to-web-design"/>
    <title>My Article on The Student's Guide To Web Design</title>
    <published>2012-09-14T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-09-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had been talking with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jannahagan.com/&quot;&gt;Janna&lt;/a&gt; about writing for her blog since June. I had been so busy that I just didn&#39;t have the time to sit down and write something (or maybe it was lack of inspiration? I don&#39;t know). Finally, last week I sat down and was able to write close to 800 words on &lt;em&gt;setting yourself up right&lt;/em&gt;. I&#39;m really happy and excited about this article.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/always-changing-things-up</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/always-changing-things-up"/>
    <title>Always Changing Things Up</title>
    <published>2012-09-14T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-09-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What a shock that this site got another refresh right? Well, I&#39;m happy to push this new design out. I&#39;ve been learning a lot in the past couple of weeks and one of those things is SCSS. I can&#39;t believe I hadn&#39;t used this in my daily workflow before. I was introduced to it at the beginning of this year by my pal &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kenearley&quot;&gt;Ken Earley&lt;/a&gt;. It wasn&#39;t until recently that I&#39;ve been working with it more closely and I&#39;m amazed at how much time you can save by using it. I&#39;ll be creating a screencast later this week to show you some of the power of SCSS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this new site is built with more semantic code (I&#39;m trying to use elements like &lt;code&gt;header&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;footer&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;article&lt;/code&gt;) and SCSS. I also think the new design is a lot cleaner and easy to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly though, there have been a lot of changes recently, both personally and professionally. Some have been good and others have been bad. It&#39;s been tough to deal with some of the mistakes I&#39;ve made recently but, I chose not to focus on the negative. I want to focus on the positive; how I can make better decisions moving forward and see the benefits of these soon. This is a lot more mushy than I normally am on here but, to sum up, I&#39;m confident that I&#39;m now headed in the right direction and things are looking very bright.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-east-wing-episode-with-bermon-painter</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-east-wing-episode-with-bermon-painter"/>
    <title>New East Wing Episode with Bermon Painter</title>
    <published>2012-09-12T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-09-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had the honor of talking with &lt;a href=&quot;http://bermonpainter.com/&quot;&gt;Bermon Painter&lt;/a&gt; who gave an excellent talk about CSS Pre-processors at &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontenddesignconference.com/&quot;&gt;The Front-End Conf&lt;/a&gt;. He&#39;s a real cool and smart guy and the episode turned out to be really educational.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/videos/workin-with-svgs</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/videos/workin-with-svgs"/>
    <title>Workin’ with SVG’s</title>
    <published>2012-09-05T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-09-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Show Notes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;show-notes&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://css-tricks.com/video-screencasts/113-creating-and-using-a-custom-icon-font/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;#113: Creating and Using a Custom Icon Font&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.somerandomdude.com/2012/08/12/svg-css-injection/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SVG CSS Injection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://simurai.com/post/20251013889/svg-stacks&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SVG Stacks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/keeping-it-realtime-conference</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/keeping-it-realtime-conference"/>
    <title>Keeping It Realtime Conference</title>
    <published>2012-09-05T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-09-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2012/09/krtconf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Keeping It Realtime Conference&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may already know, I recently changed jobs and am now working with the wonderful people at &lt;a href=&quot;http://andyet.net/&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;yet&lt;/a&gt;. Well, they throw this totally awesome conference called &lt;a href=&quot;http://2012.krtconf.com/&quot;&gt;The Keeping It Realtime Conference&lt;/a&gt; which is place to learn all about realtime technologies. I&#39;m so excited to be going out to Portland. You should come! Tickets are selling fast so, get one while you can!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/interview-on-noupe</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/interview-on-noupe"/>
    <title>Interview on Noupe</title>
    <published>2012-09-04T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-09-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was recently asked by the editor of Noupe, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/rob_e_bowen&quot;&gt;Rob Bowen&lt;/a&gt;, for an interview. I was shocked and honored to be asked. I&#39;ve known Rob for a couple of years and he came up with some great questions. If you&#39;re interested, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.noupe.com/spotlight/interview-with-designer-podcaster-tim-smith-71113.html&quot;&gt;read the interview&lt;/a&gt; and let me know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-east-wing-episode-with-jason-vanlue</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-east-wing-episode-with-jason-vanlue"/>
    <title>New East Wing Episode with Jason VanLue</title>
    <published>2012-08-29T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-08-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had the awesome pleasure of talking with Jason VanLue for an hour. In case you don&#39;t know, he&#39;s the Design Lead at &lt;a href=&quot;http://envylabs.com/&quot;&gt;Envy Labs&lt;/a&gt;, the makers of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codeschool.com/&quot;&gt;Code School&lt;/a&gt;. It was a great conversation and if you&#39;re into learning something new everyday, you should &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net/episodes/24-jason&quot;&gt;take a listen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/videos/the-french-press-experience</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/videos/the-french-press-experience"/>
    <title>The French Press Experience</title>
    <published>2012-08-23T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-08-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My pal &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mettamatt&quot;&gt;Matt Westgate&lt;/a&gt; introduced me to this video. It&#39;s brilliantly hilarious.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-aaron-irizarry-and-adam-connor</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-episode-of-the-east-wing-with-aaron-irizarry-and-adam-connor"/>
    <title>New Episode of The East Wing with Aaron Irizarry and Adam Connor</title>
    <published>2012-08-22T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-08-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I got the chance to record with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thisisaaronslife.com/&quot;&gt;Aaron Irizarry&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://adamconnor.com/&quot;&gt;Adam Connor&lt;/a&gt;. It was a really awesome conversation about design critique and was über educational for me and I hope it is for you too.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/an-email-can-make-your-day</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/an-email-can-make-your-day"/>
    <title>An Email Can Make Your Day</title>
    <published>2012-08-17T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-08-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hey Tim,&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Just wanted to say I love your show. I&#39;m a newer web designer (1.5 years) and former tv news videojournalist so I got to work with a lot of reporters and conduct a lot of interviews as well. From both angles you do a great job of getting guests to open up and share their knowledge and experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning, I woke up to that email. It made my day. This is not an effort to inflate my ego. What made my day was that he is finding my rinky-dink show useful. He&#39;s enjoying the guests and it&#39;s my hope that the show is helping him learn a thing or two in his new industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, it just drills home that if you&#39;re nice and you work hard, great things happen. The show has helped me personally in so many ways and I&#39;m so glad it helps others too.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-east-wing-episode-with-sam-soffes</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-east-wing-episode-with-sam-soffes"/>
    <title>New East Wing Episode with Sam Soffes</title>
    <published>2012-08-15T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-08-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I sat down with &lt;a href=&quot;http://samsoff.es/&quot;&gt;Sam Soffes&lt;/a&gt;, the creator of &lt;a href=&quot;https://cheddarapp.com/&quot;&gt;Cheddar&lt;/a&gt;. It was awesome! Sam is a real down to earth guy. We talk about Cheddar, retiring at 25 and his consulting rate among other things.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/cheddar-for-mac-is-out</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/cheddar-for-mac-is-out"/>
    <title>Cheddar for Mac Is Out!</title>
    <published>2012-08-15T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-08-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net/episodes/22-sam&quot;&gt;interviewed Sam&lt;/a&gt; earlier this week and even before that, I was a big fan of &lt;a href=&quot;https://cheddarapp.com/&quot;&gt;Cheddar&lt;/a&gt;. Today, he announced the Mac app for Cheddar and it&#39;s amazingly beautiful! The UI Sam has created for the brand is really nice and the pricing is ridiculously affordable. Check it out and download the app &lt;a href=&quot;https://cheddarapp.com/mac&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/dribbble-invites-up-for-grabs</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/dribbble-invites-up-for-grabs"/>
    <title>Dribbble Invites Up For Grabs</title>
    <published>2012-08-14T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-08-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I got the awesome e-mail from Dribbble yesterday that I had 2 invitations! I like giving these out! It&#39;s always fun to see people&#39;s amazing work. So do you want an invitation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Here’s How To Win&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comment on this post with your portfolio URL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give me some context on what you&#39;ve been working on and why you want to be on Dribbble&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll announce the two winners when I&#39;ve seen portfolio&#39;s that I like. Look forward to seeing your awesome work!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-east-wing-episode-with-dave-rupert</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-east-wing-episode-with-dave-rupert"/>
    <title>New East Wing Episode with Dave Rupert</title>
    <published>2012-08-13T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-08-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, we recorded with &lt;a href=&quot;http://daverupert.com/&quot;&gt;Dave Rupert&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;http://paravelinc.com/&quot;&gt;Paravel&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://atxwebshow.com/&quot;&gt;ATX Web Show&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://shoptalkshow.com/&quot;&gt;ShopTalk Show&lt;/a&gt;. I had the chance to meet him at this years Front-End Design Conference and he&#39;s a really awesome dude.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/on-app-net</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/on-app-net"/>
    <title>Thoughts on App.net</title>
    <published>2012-08-11T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-08-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So there&#39;s been a lot of talk around this idea of &lt;a href=&quot;https://join.app.net/&quot;&gt;App.net&lt;/a&gt;. Now I&#39;ll be honest and admit that I wasn&#39;t too sold on the idea when I first heard of it. It&#39;s a paid social network after all. However, as I thought more about it, the idea became more convincing to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been involved in a couple of businesses that failed and a prevalent pattern seems to be that lack of confidence to charge for the product you&#39;re selling. When you don&#39;t charge for your product, you need someone to fund it. Who? VC&#39;s. Angel investors. These people become your customers, the one&#39;s you cater to and the products become crap for the actual people who need to use it. That&#39;s what&#39;s happening with Twitter and will become more and more apparent as time goes by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://join.app.net&quot;&gt;App.net&lt;/a&gt; promises to not go down this route because it&#39;s a paid service. Who&#39;d use a paid social network? Honestly, I don&#39;t know. I think there are parts of this business model which aren&#39;t being thought about. I mostly agree with &lt;a href=&quot;http://samsoff.es/posts/app-net-is-dreaming-small&quot;&gt;Sam&#39;s thoughts&lt;/a&gt;, they&#39;re not dreaming big enough&amp;hellip; yet. But, I do feel that they have a good idea and are headed in the right direction. They&#39;re being upfront and gutsy and as a paying customer, I&#39;ll be cared for and won&#39;t have ads shoved in my face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope more people jump on this bandwagon and it&#39;s also my hope that third-party developers that have been treated badly by Twitter can begin to develop on the App.net platform (I&#39;m looking at you Tweetbot!). If you decide to join, I&#39;m &lt;a href=&quot;https://alpha.app.net/ttimsmith&quot;&gt;@ttimsmith&lt;/a&gt; as always.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I&#39;m looking forward to seeing how this plays out. I don&#39;t know if it&#39;ll be successful. I don&#39;t know if I&#39;ll later regret writing this. But, I respect a business that&#39;s willing to charge for a product that our society seems to value at nothing. Quality has a price and unfortunately it&#39;s undervalued. You always get what you pay for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; App.net has been funded!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-art-directed-article-on-style</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-art-directed-article-on-style"/>
    <title>New Art Directed Article on Style</title>
    <published>2012-08-10T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-08-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m going thru this list of articles that I once published on this very site and now republishing them on &lt;a href=&quot;http://timlikestowrite.com&quot;&gt;timlikestowrite.com&lt;/a&gt;. This particular one, I wrote back in March of 2011. I&#39;m trying not to edit them because I 2011 Tim to shine through and let me tell you, he sounds horrible. Either way, it&#39;s fun to read over things I wrote a long time ago. It&#39;s a great to see how much has changed in the way I think and lessons I&#39;ve learned. Anyway, go check it out!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/update-to-the-feed</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/update-to-the-feed"/>
    <title>Update to the Feed</title>
    <published>2012-08-09T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-08-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi Everyone! So I deleted the old feed and created a new one. Why? The old one had ads on it back when I believed in “monetizing” everything (I was so stupid). The problem was, I couldn’t delete the ads anymore. I had done some type of intricate who-knows-what and was now stuck. The only way out was to delete the feed and start fresh so that’s what I did. You can now subscribe to the new feed &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/timothybsmith&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or with the RSS link above. As always, thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/videos/thank-you-chris</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/videos/thank-you-chris"/>
    <title>Thank You Chris</title>
    <published>2012-08-09T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-08-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was watching &lt;a href=&quot;http://css-tricks.com/video-screencasts/103-integrating-fitvids-js-into-wordpress/&quot;&gt;this tutorial&lt;/a&gt; on how to integrate FitVids.js onto my site and this is the video he used as a test. It’s absolutely hilarious. You’ve got to watch it. As a side note, notice that the video above is responsive. Oh yeah...&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-industry-radio-show-episode-17</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-industry-radio-show-episode-17"/>
    <title>The Industry Radio Show - Episode 17</title>
    <published>2012-08-07T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-08-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last Thursday, I was invited to be on &lt;a href=&quot;http://theindustry.cc/2012/08/07/17-the-art-of-wireframing-a-new-messaging-protocol-mountain-lion-and-rocking-the-baby&quot;&gt;The Industry Radio Show&lt;/a&gt;. I couldn&#39;t believe it! It was a lot of fun. We talked about &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net&quot;&gt;The East Wing&lt;/a&gt;, working at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lullabot.com&quot;&gt;Lullabot&lt;/a&gt; and a lot more. &lt;a href=&quot;http://theindustry.cc/2012/08/07/17-the-art-of-wireframing-a-new-messaging-protocol-mountain-lion-and-rocking-the-baby&quot;&gt;Take a listen!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-east-wing-gets-a-refresh</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/the-east-wing-gets-a-refresh"/>
    <title>The East Wing Gets a Refresh</title>
    <published>2012-08-06T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-08-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I&#39;ve launched version three of The East Wing theme. I&#39;m excited. I&#39;m excited not only because of the new design (tons of improvements have been made), I&#39;m also excited because of the great attention the show has received and the people that it&#39;s helped. When I first started the show, I wanted to learn from people who are much smarter than me. I wanted to find out whatever information I could get so that I could improve. I&#39;ve learned a lot in the last six months and I&#39;m finally on the way to becoming the designer I want to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It makes me happy to see how people have really enjoyed the show. Personally, I&#39;ve always had a love for broadcasting so this show was a perfect merge of two great passions of mine: broadcasting and design. Even if no one would&#39;ve ever listened, I would&#39;ve continued on but, I can&#39;t explain how amazing it is to see that the show helps people with their work and inspires them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The East Wing has some very exciting times on the horizon. I&#39;ve gotten into a good grove and people enjoy the guests we talk to. If you haven&#39;t already, I invite you to listen to the show and take a peek at the new design. I hope it makes the experience better for you when listening and looking for episodes. Thank you from the bottom of my heart for your support.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/net-magazine-mike-monteiro-on-handling-clients</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/net-magazine-mike-monteiro-on-handling-clients"/>
    <title>.net Magazine: Mike Monteiro on Handling Clients</title>
    <published>2012-07-26T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-07-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When I walk into a pitch I have no idea how to solve a client’s problem, but I’m confident that I have a process for figuring it out. It’s the process that you pitch. Not the solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is such an awesome answer. I feel like we can be quick to give or offer solutions to problems when we haven&#39;t actually done the research. As designers, we need to stick to our process and make sure it&#39;s in place in every project we work on. It&#39;s the only way we can truly solve problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-art-directed-article-on-wireframing</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/new-art-directed-article-on-wireframing"/>
    <title>New Art Directed Article on Wireframing</title>
    <published>2012-07-23T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-07-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Wireframing without a design brief can be assimilated to taking a calculus test without actually taking the class. Sure, you can do without but, you don’t have the necessary information to know what problems to solve and how to solve them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been working on an article about wireframing and the design process and was finally able to finish it and post it. It resides at my new art directed site, &lt;a href=&quot;http://timlikestowrite.com/the-importance-of-wireframing&quot;&gt;timlikestowrite.com&lt;/a&gt;. You should check it out!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/tim-likes-to-write</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/tim-likes-to-write"/>
    <title>Tim Likes To Write</title>
    <published>2012-07-10T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-07-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The site is called Tim Likes To Write and it’s truer now more than ever. The truth is we should all be finding time to write and put our thoughts down on paper (whether it’s done literally or figuratively).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I launched a new site! I&#39;m not one to launch new sites often so this is really exciting for me. It&#39;ll be the place where I put longer thoughts and more thought out articles. Also, you might see guest writers from time to time. I hope you like the new site and I look forward to hearing your feedback!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; This site no longer exists.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/i-put-comments-on-my-site</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/i-put-comments-on-my-site"/>
    <title>I Put Comments on My Site</title>
    <published>2012-07-05T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-07-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yup. That&#39;s right. I put comments on here. I&#39;m actually kind of excited about it. Jason Van Lue wrote a great small post the other day on &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.jasonvanlue.com/post/26438772365/write&quot;&gt;writing&lt;/a&gt;. He&#39;s a new guy I&#39;ve been following after his great talk at the Front-End Design Conference. The part I found especially interesting was this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this digital age not only is it incredibly easy to put the proverbial pen to paper, but the barrier for ‘acceptable’ writing is much lower. It’s a time where 140 characters is the norm, so don’t hesitate just because you’re not the ‘best writer’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, that&#39;s always been what stops me. There are a myriad of more talented and skilled writers than me. Hell, they could probably express what I&#39;m thinking better than my own self. Yet, I&#39;ve seen that writing is therapeutic and in fact, gets me to delve deeper into topics and really think about them on another level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this is a really long way of saying that as you&#39;ve noticed, I&#39;m writing more here and hope you&#39;ll join in on the conversation. I also want to take this opportunity to urge you to write. Our industry thrives because there are always people willing to share what they learn and I hope you&#39;re having a part in that too.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/my-move-to-mn</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/my-move-to-mn"/>
    <title>My Move to Minnesota</title>
    <published>2012-06-25T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-06-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2012/06/welcome2MN.png&quot; alt=&quot;Welcome to Minnesota&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past week, I started a new era in my life. I finally made my move to the beautiful Land of 10,000 Lakes: Minnesota. Some of you who know me will remember that I&#39;ve been here before. You&#39;re right! About two years ago (has it been that long?) I spent six months here and fell in love with the city and people. I had the chance to make some great friends and meet very creative people who are working on awesome things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment, I&#39;m busy getting things setup and put away. It&#39;s crazy how much there is do to when you move. I&#39;ve moved plenty of times so, naturally, I thought I&#39;d be a pro. What I found out, is that nothing prepares you for a cross-country move. I will say though, what really helped out was &lt;a href=&quot;http://middaylatte.com/post/6286592516/my-cross-country-move-orlando-to-san-francisco&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; by Allison House. If you&#39;re making a big move, I really recommend you read it. It&#39;ll help you get organized and, really, for a move like this, that&#39;s the most important thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, now that I&#39;m in Minnesota, I&#39;m hoping to find a web design meetup to go to. If you have any suggestions, let me know! I also want to take this moment to give a huge thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lullabot.com/&quot;&gt;Lullabot&lt;/a&gt; for being awesome and letting me move and work wherever I want. &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net&quot;&gt;The East Wing&lt;/a&gt; will be ramping up again this week with &lt;a href=&quot;http://ethanmarcotte.com/&quot;&gt;Ethan Marcotte&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;s going to be a great episode!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, thanks for reading! I&#39;ll see y&#39;all on the internets!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/designing-in-the-browser</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/designing-in-the-browser"/>
    <title>Article on Designing “in the Browser”</title>
    <published>2012-06-01T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-06-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As web designers, we work in a vibrant industry filled with lots of ideas and many who are great at voicing strong opinions. At least for me, it&#39;s easy to get sucked into trying to get everything right and wind up focusing on the wrong things.[...] if you want to be a great web designer, focusing on the specific tools you use within your workflow is really not that helpful. Rather, focusing on how to uncover problems, how to understand users, how the technology of your medium works, how to discover and emulate beauty, and how to enjoy your work are going to be far more beneficial to your long term success!
&lt;small&gt;Jared Ponchot&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love this section from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lullabot.com/about/team/jared-ponchot&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jared&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; newest article. Really, his whole article on designing in the browser is spectacular and brings up some thought-provoking points. This is quite the hot topic in the industry at the moment and if you listen to The East Wing, you know I&#39;ve voiced my opinion on this quite a few times. However, Jared does a great job in re-focusing all of us. He&#39;s right. The tools we use aren&#39;t what matters. At the end of the day, our effectiveness in discovering and solving problems within our work is what matters. It&#39;s a great read, I really recommend you check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/the-state-of-instagram</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/the-state-of-instagram"/>
    <title>The State of Instagram</title>
    <published>2012-05-30T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-05-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Many people have been talking about Instagram lately, especially with the introduction of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/mobile/camera&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Facebook Camera&lt;/a&gt;. My pal, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.adellecharles.com/facebook-camera-instagram&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Adelle Charles&lt;/a&gt; wrote about it on her blog and she brings up some interesting points. I was also reading a new review of the app on iPhone Appstorm with the title being: &lt;em&gt;Instagram is Reborn as Facebook Camera&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am on my knees, begging that this isn&#39;t accurate. It&#39;s funny how worked up we can get over a simple app but, that&#39;s just it. It&#39;s not just an app. These companies become part of how we do things everyday and we live in a society where these more successful startups (Facebook, Twitter and Google) seem to be buying everything.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Y&#39;all remember Tweetie? Remember how absolutely beautiful it was? Remember how it was the best Twitter client and pioneered UI patterns that are still in use today? Then Twitter came in, bought it and eventually it became the crap it is today.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;I fear the same is happening to Instagram. I will gladly give you of my hard earned money if you make something awesome. In this case, I would&#39;ve gladly payed for Instagram (This is the guy that downloaded the completely leaked Drake album and proceeded to pay for it when it came out a week later). I genuinely care for people that make things I like and if I could&#39;ve had a part in Instagram not becoming part of Facebook&#39;s massive monopoly, that would&#39;ve made me happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To those of you who are entrepreneurs and making new apps, charge from the beginning. If you make something of value, people will pay for it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/alleged-iphone</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/alleged-iphone"/>
    <title>New Leaked iPhone 5 Pictures!</title>
    <published>2012-05-29T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-05-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2012/05/9to5macblackandwhite_large_verge_medium_landscape.png&quot; alt=&quot;9to5 Mac Picture of iPhone 5&quot; /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two separate iPhone part suppliers have leaked nearly identical-looking versions of what appears to be a backplate for Apple’s next iPhone, both of which support rumors of the device’s lengthened body and redesigned dock connector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is so exciting! I’m really looking forward to the release of the iPhone 5. I’m really happy about the larger screen size. However, I do have to say I’m a bit disappointed that the dock connector has been redesigned. If that turns out to be true, I think it’ll be a headache. A lot of us have multiple Apple products and up until now, they awesomely share the same charger. What do you think? Are you excited about the new iPhone?&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/pro-designers-on-facebook</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/pro-designers-on-facebook"/>
    <title>Pro Designers have their say on Facebook</title>
    <published>2012-05-24T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-05-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I’d love to get my hands on the Facebook UX and UI. There’s so many things I feel could be improved upon, but I’m sure they stay the same because they work towards the intended goals and purposes of Facebook very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the top designers reside at Facebook at the moment so there must be solid reasoning behind why elements work the way they do...
&lt;small&gt;Sarah Parmenter&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really liked this post on the Creative Bloq and I love &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sazzy.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Sarah&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; answer. The truth is, it&#39;s so easy to go around saying that an interface could be more polished. Personally, I&#39;d love to see the amazing that Sarah would do with Facebook (would it be pink?). I, like most people, am not really happy with what&#39;s been happening with the Facebook UI. However, as Sarah points out, no one knows better than the designers that actually work there what the goals and purposes are behind the design decisions. In my humble opinion, that might be something we don&#39;t always agree with but must respect.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/live-to-work</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/live-to-work"/>
    <title>The Real Reasons You’re Working So Hard...</title>
    <published>2012-05-24T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-05-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 31% of college-educated male workers are regularly logging 50 or more hours a week at work, up from 22% in 1980. Forty percent of American adults get less than seven hours of sleep on weekdays, reports the National Sleep Foundation, up from 31% in 2001.
&lt;small&gt;Bloomberg Business Week&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was doing research for a talk I&#39;ll be giving in June titled, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/UX-Speakeasy-San-Diego/events/59904042/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Work to Live, Don&#39;t Live to Work&lt;/a&gt;, and I found these statistics very interesting. To tell you the truth, it doesn&#39;t surprise me in the least. The fact of the matter is this: There are only 24 hours in a day and if you&#39;re using more hours for work, what more important things are you missing out on? The full article has a wealth of information and if you&#39;re in the San Diego area, you should come see my presentation!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/responsive-design-bookmarklet</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/responsive-design-bookmarklet"/>
    <title>Responsive Design Bookmarklet</title>
    <published>2012-05-23T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-05-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I stumbled across this bad boy because of &lt;a href=&quot;http://lukesbeard.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Luke Beard&lt;/a&gt; and I can&#39;t wait to see how this will help my development process. Until now, I had tested a couple of different tools and so far, none of them really worked like I&#39;d like them to. You should check this out and let me know if you like it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/janna</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/janna"/>
    <title>The View for Designers with Janna Hagan</title>
    <published>2012-05-23T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-05-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This particular episode of The East Wing is a special one. Not only was the conversation with Janna great, it was the first episode with Galen as my co-host. I really think y&#39;all will love this new arrangement. He brings something special to the show with his opinions, great questions and &quot;Galen&#39;s Topic of the Week&quot;. If you haven&#39;t already, I invite you to subscribe to the show. It&#39;s a great one.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/new-beginnings</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/new-beginnings"/>
    <title>New Beginnings</title>
    <published>2012-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So as you may have noticed the site got a bit of a refresh. I&#39;ve been working diligently on the new Lullabot.com and I was inspired to rethink my own site. I decided to finally treat my site as I would a client site (for the most part). Create a type of creative brief, wireframe key pages, and pay attention to the details of the site (i.e. textures, hover effects and, yes, an adaptive layout).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were many things that bothered me about the old site and I&#39;ve done my best to address them. Mostly, I had a problem with not only the display of content but, the creation of it as well. I&#39;m the type to find interesting links all the time and often have small pieces I&#39;d like to share. This design will make that easy. My pal &lt;a href=&quot;http://galengidman.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Galen&lt;/a&gt;, helped me create a post format for links. I&#39;m so thankful for his help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My larger pieces, however, will mostly live on the Lullabot blog. I&#39;m so happy to be working there and I&#39;m excited to be playing a role in the design team and in creating design related content together with my awesome teammate &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/jponch&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jared Ponchot&lt;/a&gt;. With that said, if I think of something that doesn&#39;t fit there, it will always have a home here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, I&#39;d appreciate any feedback and constructive criticism that you might have about the site. Thanks for reading and your continued support.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/links/article-on-lullabot</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/links/article-on-lullabot"/>
    <title>Constructive Criticism</title>
    <published>2012-05-14T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-05-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re at a time where technology is moving a lot faster than we can sometimes design for. That means we&#39;ll make mistakes. We&#39;ll have content that we don&#39;t know how to deliver on every device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote my first article on the Lullabot Blog! It&#39;s on Constructive Criticism. I find that this trend to publicly shame people about the work they&#39;re doing is wrong and isn&#39;t the way to make the web a better place. It&#39;s a quick read; something small you can digest during a break in your work day. Hope you enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/having-fun-and-be-happy</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/having-fun-and-be-happy"/>
    <title>Having Fun and Be Happy</title>
    <published>2012-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2012/03/lullabot-lead.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lullabot Logo&quot; title=&quot;lullabot-lead&quot; /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There&#39;s no need to sacrifice happiness for success. We believe that happiness, fun, and general silliness bring with them an energy which fuels creativity and innovation, creates a more open and communicative workplace, and makes for a more productive, more dedicated team. It&#39;s also just more fun. We try to focus on the positive and downplay competition and negativism. We are grateful for our successes and celebrate them.
  &lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lullabot.com/values&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lullabot Core Values&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isn&#39;t that awesome? I love the sound of that and I&#39;m so happy and excited to now be working with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lullabot.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lullabot&lt;/a&gt;. Lullabot is the world&#39;s top Drupal consulting and education company. They&#39;re responsible for creating websites for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grammy.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Grammy&#39;s&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marthastewart.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Martha Stewart&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wwe.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WWE&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lullabot.com/services/clients&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means I&#39;m no longer working at &lt;a href=&quot;http://getworksimple.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WorkSimple&lt;/a&gt; and I&#39;d like to take this time to thank the wonderful people there, for the opportunity to work with them. I learned so much from the team and I can&#39;t wait to see the great things they&#39;re in the process of releasing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll also be attending my first conference: &lt;a href=&quot;http://denver2012.drupal.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DrupalCon Denver&lt;/a&gt;! I&#39;ll be tweeting and checking in like crazy and if you&#39;ll be there, &lt;a href=&quot;/contact&quot;&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt;! I&#39;d love to meet ya!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, thank you for reading and your support! I&#39;m excited about this new opportunity at Lullabot and look forward to the projects I&#39;ll be working on.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/videos/on-podcasting</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/videos/on-podcasting"/>
    <title>On Podcasting</title>
    <published>2012-02-22T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-02-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wanted to create a quick screencast that goes over the basics on setting up Podpress, a plugin for Wordpress that is made for podcasting. We go through creating a feed, running it through feedburner and submitting to the iTunes store. Hope you find this useful!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Video Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;show-notes&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/podpress/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;podPress plugin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/itunes/podcasts/specs.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;iTunes Podcast Specs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feedburner.google.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Feedburner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/thoughts-on-designing-for-emotion</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/thoughts-on-designing-for-emotion"/>
    <title>Thoughts on Designing for Emotion</title>
    <published>2012-02-20T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-02-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2012/02/emotionpic1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Designin for Emotion&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m a firm believer that the day you stop learning is the day you die. I&#39;d describe myself as a self starter, always looking for new things to learn and existing skills that need refinement. Since I still have lots to live (hopefully), I also have lots to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to college for about two years yet, I didn&#39;t learn as much as I would&#39;ve liked or even what I needed to learn. Therefore, I&#39;m mostly self taught. I&#39;ve spent countless, non-billable hours, experimenting with HTML, CSS and other design and dev personal projects, in an effort to better myself and improve my craft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, that&#39;s quite a big intro into the real topic of this post. I&#39;d like to give my thoughts on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abookapart.com/products/designing-for-emotion&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Designing for Emotion&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://aarronwalter.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Aarron Walter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s start off by saying that it&#39;s absolutely awesome. If you&#39;ve read the other books that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abookapart.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A Book Apart&lt;/a&gt; has published, you&#39;d expect nothing less so, let me convince you why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Content&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content of this book is great. Aarron know&#39;s what he&#39;s talking about and that comes across every sentence you read. The extensive research is evident and each statement, study and example convince you more that this is the right way of designing for the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading this book, as with a lot of the different articles I read, I realize how much I still have to learn and put into practice. For me, it&#39;s exciting to see how I can improve and quickly implement these techniques into my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prevalent theme is to inject personality into a website. Aarron emphasizes that a website is human too and offers logical ways to make this happen. Designing personas is an amazing idea and just one of many practical tips he offers. Anyone working on a product needs to read this. It&#39;s guaranteed to bring the level of work you produce to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something interesting to note about this book is the constant studies of psychology and the human brain. This was especially helpful as many of the studies are something I would&#39;ve never imagined to research and have really helped me understand how we, as humans, respond and react to design. Aarron explains that we make decisions on emotion not logic; interestingly, making designing for emotion such a logical choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprise is always followed by a proportional emotional response[...] There&#39;s not enough time for deep, intellectual contemplation, so the brain relies on emotion to provide a &quot;gut reaction.&quot;
&lt;small&gt;Aarron Walter, Designing For Emotion&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Tone&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I love about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abookapart.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A Book Apart&lt;/a&gt; is the tone of the books published. I&#39;ve read the other books in the collection and it&#39;s easy to recognize the way that they want the reader to feel when reading these books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aarron&#39;s writing style is witty and humorous in all the right places and he is able to explain complex design theory in terms that are understandable and easily applicable. I found myself laughing quite a few times and having lots of &quot;Aha!&quot; moments. He talks about reverse mullets and how that relates to design: party in the front, business in the back. C&#39;mon now, that&#39;s hilarious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s truly amazing how Aarron not only is able to communicate excellently on these principles but, also putting them into practice in the book itself. The book is designed for emotional response, engaging you every step of the way and urging you to read more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to extend a personal thank you to Aarron. Thank you for writing this book and thank you for helping me do my job better. I owe him much more than what I paid for this book. If you haven&#39;t already, do yourself a favor and pick up a copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abookapart.com/products/designing-for-emotion&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Buy the Book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/apps-i-love-mac-edition</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/apps-i-love-mac-edition"/>
    <title>Apps I Love (Mac Edition)</title>
    <published>2012-02-13T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-02-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while, I get asked for app recommendations. I love giving these type of recommendations and if you follow me on twitter, you&#39;ll notice that I often ask for them too. Finding and using new apps is fun for me and I&#39;m always looking for better and simpler ways of doing things. With that said, I thought I&#39;d publish a list of some of my favorite apps in the hope of helping out some new Mac owners or point you to something you didn&#39;t know about before. You&#39;ll notice that the title of the post is &quot;Mac Edition&quot; which hints at a series!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as a side note, these apps are in no particular order. I use most of these everyday and would be at a total loss without them (which is sad). Also, I&#39;m not using any affliate links and I wasn&#39;t paid to talk about any of these apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://smilesoftware.com/TextExpander/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Text Expander&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&#39;t have Text Expander, you really need to get on this bandwagon. It&#39;s an amazing app that saves me so much time everyday. I&#39;ve programmed snippets that I use on a daily basis like my different email signatures, code snippets, my phone number, resume, etc. I save about an hour and a half of typing everyday; to me that&#39;s enough to make it&#39;s price of $34.95 worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rdio.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rdio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a little late to this party but, Wow! I&#39;m loving it. I just bought my subscription the other day and have found it extremely useful. I am at my desk most of the day and like any normal person, I love music. I&#39;ve found most or all of my favorite music and the stream is excellent. I love it because, there&#39;s always new music, playlists or friends stations that I can listen to. Also, iTunes is so bloated these days and it always runs super slow on my machine. Great alternative and beautiful UI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://macromates.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TextMate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was using Smultron in my amateur days and as I look back, I don&#39;t know how I ever made do with it. I love TextMate. The themes that are included are great and it&#39;s features are very useful. I&#39;m no expert and I&#39;m learning new features of the app all the time but, the one I have discovered like, bundles, line collapse and others have made this app just amazing to use. The great thing is, you can add more functionality too! If you&#39;re writing SCSS, you can find extentions to properly color the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iawriter.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;iA Writer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely love this app. I wrote this post in iA Writer. It&#39;s such a beautiful app with such a simple interface; it&#39;s hard not to like it. I do have to credit &lt;a href=&quot;http://adellecharles.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Adelle&lt;/a&gt; for pointing me to this app and I&#39;m glad she did. What I love about it is the seamless integration with iCloud. I can be working on a document on my Mac and then move to the couch and work on it from my iPad. Also, no formatting! The truth is, formatting takes up time and space and you don&#39;t need it to write. Writer does this excellently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sparrowmailapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sparrow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is actually a new app I just got into. I had heard such great things about it for a while. However, I didn&#39;t have my email set up with Google so, I hadn&#39;t moved over. What a mistake! I was using Postbox and although I was a loyal user for about two years, their app is a bit bloated and slows down my machine quite a bit. I run four different email accounts and not being able to switch between these effortlessly through out the day is a big downer. I&#39;m now proud to say I&#39;m using Sparrow and I love it. Beautiful UI, you can feel the attention to detail and very lightweight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://reederapp.com/mac/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Reeder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the longest time, I was using my email to receive RSS feeds. Big mistake. Not only did it clutter my inbox but, I would tend to delete articles in an effort of bringing my inbox to zero. It was an absolute mess and I wasn&#39;t reading like I would want to. Reeder is an excellent solution for me. I&#39;ve added all or most of my feeds over to Reeder and now enjoy some reading before starting the work day. It&#39;s integration with Readability make the app that more useful. I can go through the day and bookmark an article in Readability knowing that it&#39;ll be there, waiting for me in Reeder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.getharvest.com/mac&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Harvest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every contractor needs this. Actually, even if you&#39;re not a contractor, you need this. Harvest is actually a web app but, since I use the Mac App, I&#39;ll include it into this list. Harvest has simplified my life in so many ways. I can keep track of my time, easily sumbit invoices and provide estimates and it keeps track of my monthly and yearly earnings, making tax time that much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://getcloudapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cloud App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This app is amazing! I use this everyday. Yet, I believe I only use half of it&#39;s great features. I use it&#39;s Photoshop and Chrome raindrops the most. Through out the day, I&#39;ll be working on a comp and can easily upload my work and send it for feedback. Not to mention, it&#39;s a great way for me to see the progress I make on a certain interface. Also, when I go to share useful links on Twitter, I use CloudApp to shorten them. It also has Sparrow integration, allowing me to send lightweight emails with attachments in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rogueamoeba.com/audiohijackpro/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Audio Hijack Pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s make it clear from the beginning, I love this app because of the functionality not because of the design. If you have a better alternative, please let me know. It&#39;s a great app though. I use it to record the audio from Skype which is really useful when recording episodes for the podcasts I host. You can record any audio really. However, my critique about this app is it&#39;s usability. It was a bit difficult to figure out how to use the first time but, thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://nikibrown.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Niki&lt;/a&gt;, I was able to set up a bit quicker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mamp.info/en/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MAMP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but definitely not least, MAMP. If you&#39;re writing PHP or developing Wordpress themes, you need this. Setting up is quite easy but, if you need some help, &lt;a href=&quot;http://css-tricks.com/video-screencasts/86-mamp/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;watch this great video&lt;/a&gt; by Chris Coyier. I always love the way he teaches, it&#39;s so personal. Love that. I owe him for a lot of the things I know now. Anyway, this isn&#39;t about Chris, it&#39;s about MAMP. It&#39;s a great app that will allow you to work locally which is good practice. I know most of us will work directly on the server and refresh but, you&#39;ll notice quickly this isn&#39;t the right way of doing things when you break everything because of an incorrectly placed &quot;=&quot; sign. Work locally with MAMP and then push up to your server. A lot easier and faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&#39;s my list of apps I love! If you have any recommendations or suggestions of better apps, let me know! I&#39;d love to hear about them!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/here-the-latest</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/here-the-latest"/>
    <title>Here’s the Latest</title>
    <published>2012-01-30T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-01-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This Saturday, I finally decided it was time to get serious about my sites and actually host them somewhere reliable. I&#39;m happy to say that my three awesome sites (&lt;a href=&quot;http://laughifyouwanttoo.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Laugh If You Want Too&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The East Wing&lt;/a&gt; and this one) are now hosted with the very trust worthy &lt;a href=&quot;http://mediatemple.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Media Temple&lt;/a&gt;. I&#39;m not getting paid for advertising them, I&#39;ve just really liked the service so far. The hosting is a major upgrade from what I had before and it&#39;s very affordable. At the time of writing this, their Grid Service is only $20/month. That&#39;s not bad, not bad at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d also like to give my sincerest thank you to Chris Coyier from CSS-Tricks for &lt;a href=&quot;http://css-tricks.com/video-screencasts/46-domains-dns-hosting-and-google-apps/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this screencast&lt;/a&gt;. He goes into detail on how to move a domain&#39;s DNS to point to Media Temple and how to setup email with Google Apps. It only took me a couple of hours to move everything and get the sites up and running. Real time saver!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;I Have a Job&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m really excited to announce that I&#39;m now happily pushing pixels at &lt;a href=&quot;http://getworksimple.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WorkSimple, Inc.&lt;/a&gt; I found them in late December via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.authenticjobs.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Authentic Jobs&lt;/a&gt; and really fell in love with the company and the product. I&#39;ve been working with them a couple days shy of a month now and it&#39;s been an awesome ride. The work I&#39;ve been involved with has been really challenging and exciting and I also have the privilege of working with a great team that I&#39;m learning a lot from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, this week I&#39;m learning HAML and SCSS. If you haven&#39;t looked into it, it&#39;s revolutionary. It&#39;ll change the way you code forever. Now, I might be late to the party on this one but, I was completely geeking out the other day when &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/kenearley&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ken&lt;/a&gt;, one of our front-end devs, was giving me a crash course. I owe him tons of money now for allowing me to pick his brain. I highly recommend reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alistapart.com/articles/getting-started-with-sass/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; if you&#39;re interested in Sass. I&#39;m telling you, it&#39;s absolutely revolutionary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The East Wing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People, keep an eye out for &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The East Wing&lt;/a&gt;. Things are really revving up for this. I&#39;m really excited and hope you are too. At the moment we have guests lined up for Episodes 1-5 and trust me, we&#39;ll be talking to some awesome people, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linkedin.com/in/benmoore&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ben Moore&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://kennedysgarage.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chris Kennedy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://nikibrown.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Niki Brown&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://zerply.com/justinstyle/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Justin Style&lt;/a&gt;, just to name a few. It&#39;d be a real shame for you to miss out on this so, head on over to the website and sign up for our newsletter. We&#39;ll be launching February 15th so, put it in your calendars!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re interested on being on the show and you&#39;re working on an interesting product or project, email us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hello@theeastwing.net&quot;&gt;hello@theeastwing.net&lt;/a&gt; and I promise to respond as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, thank you for reading and if you have thoughts you&#39;d like to share, give me a shout on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/timothybsmith&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://ttimsmith.com/articles/fresh-new-look</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://ttimsmith.com/articles/fresh-new-look"/>
    <title>Fresh New Look!</title>
    <published>2012-01-09T00:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-01-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Smith</name>
      <uri>http://ttimsmith.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, I’ve got a brand new site... again. It almost seems that I’m redesigning this crap too much. But, the truth is, there are always better ways to solve problems and I strive to do that with all of my work, even my personal stuff. With that said, the site I had up before honestly looked a bit amateurish. I don’t know what I was thinking. I mean, it did only take about two hours to design and code it up so, that might explain things a bit. Either way, moving forward, there were a couple of things I wanted to get better at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;My Work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, a lot of work that I’ve done is restricted by NDA’s and that’s all great when you’re working on these exciting projects but, when it comes time to display them, it’s horrible. Therefore, at the moment I can only show snippets of my work for which &lt;a href=&quot;http://dribbble.com/timothybsmith&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dribbble&lt;/a&gt; has been super useful. For now, that won’t change. But the truth is though, my design isn’t the only thing I’m working on at the moment. I have a pretty cool podcast called &lt;a href=&quot;http://laughifyouwanttoo.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Laugh If You Want Too&lt;/a&gt; and a soon to be podcast called &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The East Wing&lt;/a&gt; which is going to be awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having said that, I wanted this new design to give people the opportunity to see all of my stuff. I know I’m no internet celebrity but, if you’re interested, now you can find it. Which reminds me &amp;lt;rant&amp;gt; I’m no internet celebrity and I probably will never be but, why can’t people reply to tweets of us unknown peeps? I don’t get it. Maybe you’re too busy or you don’t care for the people that admire your work. Who knows. One thing is true though, if you want to talk and interact with me, I’ll always reply. To know who you are, you gotta know where you came from. &amp;lt;/rant&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Writing Again&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m happy to report that my writing juices seem to be flowing again which is why I dedicated more time to the design of this site. I want to have somewhere to pour some of my thoughts. As I grow as a designer and a person, I find it essential to share the small bits of wisdom you find along the way. Again, it may not be a lot; I still have much to learn in design and in life but, I’ll always be thankful to those that helped me when I was starting out. It’s about time I pay that forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Thank You&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just want to extend a huge thank you to those whom have supported me and have been interested in the different things I do. I also want to extend a thank you to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.andytlr.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Andy Taylor&lt;/a&gt;, the creator of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://cssgrid.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;1140px CSS Grid&lt;/a&gt;; it’s the reason why making this site responsive was a cinch! Check it out if you haven’t already! Also, I big thank you to &lt;a href=&quot;http://kennedysgarage.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kennedy&lt;/a&gt;, who took me out of a bind and helped me figure out how to change the color of a placeholder in a form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, you’ll notice that this blog is proudly brought to you by &lt;a href=&quot;carbonads.net&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Carbon Ads&lt;/a&gt;. Adelle and her team are awesome and always on the look out for great companies for their network. Do yourself a favor and click on some of these ads. Yes, you’d be helping me make some money, but you’d be getting in some awesome products as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, thank you for reading and if you have thoughts you’d like to share, give me a shout on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/timothybsmith&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
 
</feed>